we created scrum to help teams function
a lot better in software development
one of the problems in software development
as projects are always late and
developers are under pressure and the
question was could we build a high-performing team like a sports team
where they could execute five to ten times faster than a normal team
and based on a lot of experience with Silicon Valley teams
and experience I've
had in many companies we figured out how
to do that
so for example my last company we started doing scrum in 2000
we built the teams there working together
it took teams when they're starting off can very quickly start working together
maybe going twice as fast
and then as they get their engineering practices
really working well
their velocity will accelerate
by 2005 my last company had
reached a state where they were running 10 times as fast as one of our outsource
waterfall teams in India
so it would cost us three times as much to get
software developed in India as it would do it to do it right here in Boston
that
allowed us to we had a meeting every week where the chief product owner
and scrum who was my who was working the backlog and the direction of the company
he could meet with all the stakeholders and decide ok,
this week what are the key
issues, what are the issues with the teams
what are the issues of the market,
what are the sales guys seeing
and he could change the backlog
so the next two weeks they were adjusting the direction of the technology development
and two weeks later they could have a new
release of the software to target directly the competition
so as Scott
Maxwell here at open your venture
partners points out he likes the idea
you know you line up the Canada boom
you take care of that part of the competition then two weeks later you
move in the Canada boom
so with thatspeed and performance and to get that
speed the teams have to be really excited and enthusiastic
you can't do it by forcing it so they really have to
learn how to work together,
get the engineering practices really good and
then they could go very fast
the tipicall traditional product development team
in the space of my last company was doing - we - releases a year one release
every six months
as they hit their peak of performance in 2005 they were doing
45 releases a year
when you are doing 45 releases and your competition can only
do two,
it is game over we had no more competition
so that's the that's one of
the goals of scrum from the point of view of the business side