in this section we'll learn all about the daily scrum meeting
we will cover the inputs to the meeting the goal who attends the time box the general approach to running the meeting and the output
once a day the development team holds the daily scrum meeting
the goal of this meeting is to inspect and adapt the ongoing work of the Sprint
the time box is short 15 minutes
and so it is important for the development team to be highly focused during the meeting
the scrum master has three responsibilities related to the meeting
first the scrum master ensures that the development team has the meeting
second the scrum master ensures that others outside of the development team do not participate
and third the scrum master teaches the development team how to keep the meeting within the 15 minute time box
this implies that the scrum master does not lead the meeting in a traditional sense
once the development team has mastered the time box and the meeting is a regular part of the team's daily work,
the scrum master may choose not to attend
or may choose to attend in a purely neutral and facilitative role
the daily scrum meeting is typically held at the same time in place each day to reduce complexity
during the meeting members of the development team explain their progress and plans in three areas
what did i do yesterday to help the development team meet the Sprint goal?
what will I do today to help the development team meet the Sprint goal?
do I see any impediment that prevents me or the development team from meeting the Sprint goal?
the inputs to the meeting then are the Sprint goal
and the Sprint backlog
which is the development teams plan for how they will achieve the Sprint goal
to maintain the time box the daily scrum is focused on the transparency
and inspect portions of the empirical process
it is critical that the entire development team is present to reach that shared understanding
the adapt portion very often requires the input of only a subset of the development team
those involved with the portions of work that need to be adapted that day to meet the Sprint goal
for this reason
it is common for some set of the development team to meet directly after the daily scrum has concluded
they discuss how to self organize around any issues that were raised
adapting the affected portions of the sprint backlog
the adapted sprint backlog is the primary output of the daily scrum meeting
effective daily scrum meetings have several benefits
they improve communication
they eliminate the need for other meetings
they identify impediments to development for removal
they highlight and promote quick decision-making
and they improve the development teams level of knowledge
research has shown that effective daily scrum meetings
have a high correlation with successful implementation of the scrum framework