in another section we describe the
product backlog as a constantly evolving
artifact that is never complete product
backlog refinement is the work that is
done to constantly evolve the product
backlog most product backlogs were at
some point in unsorted collection of
ideas for features enhancements
improvements and capabilities for a
product to provide transparency and
focus the product owner collaborates
with the other members of the scrum team
to refine those ideas adding details
estimates and in order to each item they
also ensure that any single product
backlog item that is likely to be pulled
into the next sprint is small enough to
reasonably reach the definition of done
within the sprint time box once the
items at the top of the ordered product
backlog have these characteristics they
are considered ready for sprint planning
while it is possible to go through
product backlog refinement for every
known item in the product backlog the
focus is usually on just enough product
backlog items to fill the next sprint or
to this just-in-time product backlog
refinement eliminates the waste that is
possible when trying to provide clarity
and detail for every known item long
before it is pulled into a sprint the
product owner and development team
collaboratively refined the product
backlog however product backlog items
can be updated at any time by the
product owner or at the product owners
discretion the development team is
responsible for providing estimates
product backlog refinement is an ongoing
activity throughout the life of a
product backlog since there is no gap
between Sprint's product backlog
refinement occurs during Sprint's and
usually consumes no more than 10% of the
capacity of the development team scrum
does not define a particular event
process or time box for product backlog
refinement so the scrum team decides how
and when refinement is done