hi and welcome to the agile Academy in
this angel' and practice talk we'd like
to show you how to Vella pers on an
agile team use peer programming to lure
defects help deliver faster and produce
higher quality work let's have a look at
how this practice works the way
developers are collaborating is a bit
like driving a car on a rally one of you
is driving while the other is navigating
reading the map while the driver is
keeping their eyes in the road the
Navigator is focusing on the destination
and how to get there regardless of the
kind of work you do you may want to try
out collaborating with a colleague in
the same way especially when you are
dealing with a difficult task
it works based if both people are peers
sharing the same role and having a
similar skill and experience level here
our bill analyst - developers from the
agile team who are delivering a new
employee performance review system for
the HR department they will be working
together side by side at the same
computer solving the same problem they
take turns using the keyboard and mouse
at the moment liz is the driver while
she is writing the code and performs
tests on that code bill as a navigator
observes her work considering the
strategic direction the next steps and
potential pitfalls he also considers if
this is a simplest design possible and
comes up with ideas for improvement
after the period of time the swap rules
and less navigates while bill drives
because they are constantly
communicating and reviewing together
they produce higher quality work at a
faster pace than either could do on
their own it also ensures that more than
just one developer knows each part of
the system peer swap places frequently
throughout the day and also new pairs
are formed to promote sharing of
knowledge throughout the team at the
same time a uniform style of planning is
carried out which makes working together
easier it also creates an ownership and
commitment to the collective code
despite the benefits peer program is not
always easy as a driver you have someone
observing you constantly and when you're
navigating you need to refrain from
rushing to point out details like
messing semicolons or typos instead you
need to get the driver time to write and
rewrite the work while you focus on the
direction the work is going also you
should consider that peer programming
isn't suitable for all tasks or
situations but
if you choose to do it you need to
respect each other communicate and make
it easy on yourselves by using a
computer with a big screen enjoy the
right in this agile and practice talk
you saw her agile teams collaborate and
use a practice of peer programming to
increase the quality of the work
you may also from time to time hear the
term peering news to this can refer to
to business people or one business
person and a developer working together
on one piece of work you can see that
building quality into a task isn't just
limited to IT folks anymore peering can
also encourage the peers to take pride
in their work because they are sharing
it with someone else if you want to
learn more about agile the agile Academy
offers a range of courses delivered by
accredited trainers and lots of open
source material which you can find on
our website if you have any questions
also feel free to contact us on our
website or drop us a line on Twitter
thank you and enjoy your agile journey