Hi! and welcome to the agile Academy
In this agile in practice talk
we'd like to give you a quick insight into stand-ups
and how they work for agile teams
Let me introduce you to the team
they are working on the new employee performance review system
and are getting together for their daily meeting
every day at the same time the team stands in a semicircle at the team wall
and turn each team member gives an update by shearing
what work that I complete yesterday?
what do I plan to complete today?
what blocker, if any, do I face and getting my work done today?
Here is Bill. kicking off the stand up
yesterday I completed the first version of the new performance review flier
and today, I will start the FAQ list
my blocker is that some of the HR experts I need to talk with aren't available
They're on a team day
bill then passes on the Talking Stick to Megan
Who shares her update with the group
(*)Megan might see
yesterday I completed not much since my computer crashed
and so today I'll be catching up with my work on testing the systems login security
new blockers since I got a temporary computer to work on
Megan passes a talking stick on to Damien
who is next?
the team purposely has this meeting while standing up
because it helps him to focus on answering just these three questions
keeping the stand up short and sharp
since they take problem resolution outside of this meeting
and the frame from storytelling
their stand up takes no more than 15 minutes at the max
guests and non core team members are welcome to the stand up
but they can only listen
and cannot actively participate
Jen the business subject-matter expert
thinks that the daily stand-up is very useful
she says
even though I don't actively participate in the stand up
I know where we are with the work as a team
if there are any issues that I can solve I get on it straight away
Megan adds
what I find challenging about the stand up
is keeping what I share relevant to my teammates
so that I don't waste our time with just some general update statements
and short stand-ups or brief daily meetings that are made to get everyone updated on the progress of the work that your team has committed to
and of any obstacles that are in the way
since you all share your updates with the whole team
as stand-up is not a micromanagement report to the project manager or team lead
the project manager is mainly there to hear about the blockers
it is his or her tasks to remove these obstacles as quickly as possible
we hope you enjoyed this Agile in practice talk
and that it encourages you to try out stand ups with your own team