hi and welcome to the agile Academy
سلام، به آکادمی چابک خوش آمدید
in this Agile and practice talk
در این گفتار از سری گفتارهای «چابکی در عمل»
we'd like to talk about test-driven development
می‌خواهیم درباره توسعه تست محور صحبت کنیم
which is commonly referred to as TDD
که عموما با عنوان TDD شناخته می‌شود
TDD is a software development discipline where
TDD دستورالعملی برای توسعه نرم افزار است که
developers write automated test cases for enhancements or new features before they write any code
بر آن اساس، توسعه دهندگان قبل از کد نویسی برای توسعه یا افزودن قابلیت جدید، باید تست‌های موردی بنویسند
the basic premise of TDD
اصل اولیه TDD این است که
is that you begin by writing a failing test for the simplest piece of functionality that you need to implement
ابتدا برای جزیی ساده‌‌ از عملکردی که می‌خواهید پیاده‌سازی کنید، تستی می‌نویسید که پاس نمی‌شود
you then write the simplest code possible to pass that test
و بعد ساده‌ترین کد ممکن، برای پاس شدن آن تست را می‌نویسید
once this is done
وقتی این کار انجام شد (تست پاس شد)
the new code is reworked or re-factored as it is better known
روی کد جدید کار می‌کنید و آن را بازسازی می‌کنید تا به شکل بهتری درآید
to ensure it meets the requirement standards of the code
برای اینکه مطمئن شوید با استانداردهای کدنویسی مطابقت دارد
so why do all this?
خب! چرا این همه کار کنیم؟
what's the benefit?
Well! there are a few.
for example
TDD helps to ensure quality by focusing on requirements before writing the code
it assists in keeping the code clear
simple and testable by breaking it down into small achievable steps
it provides documentation about how the system works for anyone coming onto the team later on
it builds a suite of repeatable regression tests
and it acts as an enabler for rapid change
Liz one of the developers on the agile team
which has been delivering a new employee performance review system for the HR department
wants to implement a new feature to the system
she has previously collaborated with the business analyst
the product owner and the tester
so that she understands and is clear about the requirements
Liz is now writing a simple automated test to fulfill the requirements
in most instances this will be what is called a unit test
after Liz has written the test
she runs it against the already existing version of the system
since the piece of code that delivers this functionality is not written yet
and so not part of the current version of the system the test fails
Liz then writes just enough code to make the test pass
at this stage the code is not perfect
but it will now pass a test the
The final step in TDD requires less to rework the code to make it simpler
more readable and maintainable
this ensures it doesn't damage the functionality that the code is meant to deliver
developers call the reworking of the code re-factoring
this happens in minutes not hours or days
we are now two weeks into the project
and a change to the feature lets previously built as needed
however Liz is on leave
so Tom another developer will need to make the change
Liz has already created a test for this feature
so tom is able to read it and understand what the code was supposed to do
he then uses the test to verify that his code doesn't break Liz's changes
once that's done Tom adds a test case of his own
this increases a test coverage
and ensures a record of his changes to Liz's code
in this agile and practice talk
You saw how Test-Driven development helps agile teams
to make rapid changes whilst ensuring high-quality
re-factoring is another agile practice
Which is a topic for another time