http://strategicdiscipline.positioningsystems.com/blog-0/west-points-pearsons-law-scrum-lesson
سلام. اینجا هستم تا درباره زندگی، رهایی و جستجوی شادمانی صحبت کنم
hello I'm here to talk about life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness
رویای بزرگِ آمریکایی‌ها، که اغلب محقق نشده است
a great American dream that's often not fulfilled
به قول رابرت بِرنز (شاعر اسکاتلندی - قرن ۱۷ میلادی)
in the words of the poet Robert Burns
«بهترین نقشه‌های آدمها و موشها، اغلب اوقات به شکل وحشتناکی غلط از آب در می‌آیند
"The best-laid plans of mice and men, often go terribly wrong"
و جای رسیدن به آرزو
به درد و رنج، ختم می‌شوند»
and lead to pain and suffering
instead of the promised hope
اولین بار که با این مشکل دست و پنجه نرم کردم، زمانی بود که دانشجوی دانشکده افسری در وست پوینت  (آکادمی نظامی ایالات متحده) بودم
I first started to wrestle with this problem as a cadet at West Point (United States Military Academy)
در دوره آموزشی، رنجها و مصیبت‌های فراوانی کشیدیم
we went through a lot of pain and suffering in our training
در آخرین سال حضورم در آنجا، من را به عنوان افسر آموزش منصوب کردند
and in the last year I was there they made me the training officer
تا گروهان ال.۲ را آموزش دهم
for company L2
چون در انجام حرکات رژه مشکل داشتند
because they had a marching problem on the parade field
گروهان ال.۲ به گروهان "شل و ول‌های بی‌عرضه" معروف بود
company L2 is known as the "Loose Deuce"
چون به مدت ۱۰۰ سال
because for a hundred years
معمولی بودن را به مثابه یک سنت پذیرفته بودند
they had a tradition of mediocrity
با عملکردی بی‌نظم و شلخته
sloppy performance
ده‌ها سال افرادی سعی کردند که آنها را بیشتر آموزش دهند
for decades people had tried to get them to march longer train harder
اما هر کاری کردند، بی‌فایده بود
but nothing worked
می‌دانستم باید کار متفاوتی بکنم
so I knew I had to do something different
خب تصمیمی که گرفتم این بود ، من نمی توانستم به آنها بگویم چه کاری انجام دهند
so what I decided to do is, I couldn't tell them what to do
اما نشانه ها و شبنماهای مشخصی برای یافتن مسیر برای آنها قرار دادم
but I could put up in the bulletin board at night and color coded notes
نشانه های که دقیقاً نمایشگر عملکرد آنها در میدان رژه بود
exactly how their performance was in the parade field
دقیقاً همان چیزی که آنها باید برای بهبود انجام دهند
in exactly what they needed to do to improve
برای مثال شما می دانید که چارلی باید با توقف شمشیر بر روی زمین
you know Charlie has got to stop sticking his sword in the ground
در میان اجرای رژه
in the middle of a parade
تا نشانی برای تغییر جهت در گوشه میدان برای سومین گردان بفرستد
the 3rd platoon has got to turn the corner
و تمامی این فعالیت ها باید در هماهنگی کامل و با دستور دقیق فرمانده انجام پذیرد
in synchronization and the commander has to enunciate his commands crisply
بدون لحظه ای درنگ یا اختلاف زمانی
in exactly right timing
به گونه ای که همه شگفت زده شوند
to everyone's amazement
در طی سه ماه این گروهان به بهترین گروهان لشکر تبدیل شد
they became the number one  company in the Corps cadets within three months
و در همان زمان ژنرال مک آرتور درگذشت
and General MacArthur died at this time
و او درخواست کرده بود تا یک گروهان از دانش آموختگان دانشکده افسری برای بدرقه تابوت او تا آرامگاهش حاضر باشند و گروهان ال.2 انتخاب شد
and he had specified there must be a company cadets marching behind his casket
to lay him to rest, and L2 was chosen
برای آخرین مراسم خاکسپاری
so for dead last
برای انجام مراسم خاکسپاری یکی از بزرگترین ژنرال های (آکادمی نظامی ایالات متحده)
to putting out one of our greatest generals in the grave
یک تحول بزرگ در یک بازه زمانی بسیار کوتاه
was a long journey in a very short period of time
بعد از آن من از وست پوینت (آکادمی نظامی ایالات متحده) فارغ التحصیل شدم و به نیروی هوایی رفتم
now I graduated from West Point and I went into the air force
در زمانی که در وست پوینت بودم من آموخته های زیادی از سایر فرماندهان داشتم
while i was at West Point I learned something from other leaders
من در اتاقی زندگی می کردم که روی پلاکی که روی گچ بری دور بخاری آن نصب شده بود ، نوشته بود
I lived in a room which were they had a plaque on the mantelpiece it said
ژنرال دوایت آیزنهاور ( سی و چهارمین رئیس جمهور ایالات متحده) اینجا می خوابیده است
general DWIGHT D. EISENHOWER slept here
هر زمان که این پلاک را می خواندم نقل قول معروفی از او را به یاد می آوردم که
and every time I'd read that plaque I'd remember
his famous quote
"برنامه ها بی ارزش هستند اما برنامه ریزی همه چیز است"
"Plans are worthless, but planning is everything"
بنابراین زمانی که به عنوان یک خلبان جنگنده در تیم شناسایی بودم ، برنامه ریزی های زیادی انجام دادیم
so when I got to be a fighter pilot I was in reconnaissance we did a lot of planning
اما یک روز یکی از خلبانان همکار من
but one day one of my fellow pilots
در حین عملیات بر روی هانوی(پایتخت ویتنام) مورد اصابت یک موشک زمین به هوای سام قرار گرفت و هواپیمای او منفجر شد
ed attebery was blown out of the air over Hanoi, by a SAM (Surface-to-Air) Missile
من با خودم گفتم که او برنامه ریزی بسیار خوبی داشت
and I said to myself he did really good planning
ولی او عموماً بر روی هدف به صورت افقی پرواز می کرد و در نهایت اقدام به گرفتن عکس می کرد
but he was flying straight and level over the target
که اینکار می تواند من را بکشتن بدهد
that could get me killed
از آن روز به بعد
from that day forward
برنامه من این بود که ببینم هدف چیست
my plan was to have a vision where the target was
and as soon as I crossed North Vietnam I went into an evasive maneuver
because every second I knew I was being fired at
and only at the last moment would i come up straight level offer a target just for a second
to snap that photo
حالا من زنده ام
now I got out of there alive
بیش از نیمی از همراهان من همچون فلوید از مأموریت خود بازنگشتند
over half the people like fluid, did not come back from their missions
و هنگامی که من به ایالات متحده برگشتم
and when I came back to the United States
سورپرایز بزرگی بود چراکه من بارها به کشته شدن نزدیک شده بودم
it was a big surprise I'd come so close to getting killed so many times
احساس می کردم
it felt like
که یک زندگی جدید به من بخشیده شده است
it was a new life.
هر روز برای من مثل یک هدیه ویژه بود
every day was like a bonus day
یک روز کامل
a free day
و این سؤال که من با این روز چیکار می توانستم بکنم
and what was I going to do with it
بنابراین من از نیروی هوایی خواستم تا من را به کشورم برگردانند
so I asked the Air Force to send me back
به آکادمی نیروی هوایی تا به عنوان یک مدرس آموزش دیده مشغول به کار شوم
to the Air Force Academy to become a trained to be a professor
یا به مدرسه آموزشی در استنفورد تا به عنوان یک آموزش دیده آکادمی نیروی هوایی ایالات متحده در آنجا مشغول به کار شوم
or back to school at Stanford trained to be a professor at the Air Force Academy
و از آنجا به دانشکده پزشکی دانشگاه کلرادو(از ایالت های جنوب غربی امریکا) رفتم
and from there I went into the University of Colorado medical school
من برای مدت یازده سال در آن دانشکده بودم
I was on the faculty they for 11 years
تا زمانی که آنجا بودم
while I was there
تخصص من ساخت سوپر مدل های کامپیوتری با استفاده از ساختار سلول های انسانی بود
my expertise was building super computer models of the human cell
و نشان دادن چگونگی تکامل آنها
and showing how it evolved
and multiplied
and what caused it to become cancerous what could make that stop
how do we cure cancer
and while I was there
a big banking company running 150 banks all over North America came by, they said
you know at the University you have the best expertise in technologies we use at the bank
you have all the knowledge and know that none of the money
but at the bank we've got all the money
and we don't know what we're doing
you should come work for the bank and it would be a perfect marriage of knowledge and money
and they may be an offer that my wife couldn't refuse a poor university professor
so I wind up at the bank and what do I see
I see they're running all these huge projects
hundreds of developers
and they manage all these projects with a Gantt chart
and this is a technology that was introduced to the military in the United States in 1910
it didn't work very well in World War one
and it didn't work very well then
because every piece of the project is lined up with a date
and if anybody misses that timing
the whole project is delayed
and when it gets delayed the customers get upset the managers get angry
that would force these developers to work nights, weekends they go on death marches
it reminded me of the Roman galleys you know
the slaves rowing rowing the whip is cracking
but as a fighter pile, I knew the essence of the problem
these guys could not land a project
you know we learned as a fighter pilot that we had very carefully bed that airplane
right on the end of the runway
and if we did
it we might go halfway down the runway and slide off the runway into the trees
and that's what they were doing every project
sliding off the runway into the trees
so I went to the CEO and I said
this Bank is totally screwed up
if you give me the worst, business unit in the bank
I will fix it, just like I fixed company L2
and he said Sutherland if you want that headache, you've got it
so I said okay
I will report to you once a month
to you in the senior management
and the rest of the time you stay out of my unit
we're going to run this as a little company at a company like a start-up
and so we broke them down into small team
sales, marketing, installs engineering everyone
all working together with team incentives
in a collaborative space
and we ran weekly cycles
we began building a backlog of what we needed to do
and I began to show them how to lay in the airplane
how is it ?
that a pilot can make a perfect touchdown
he has to look at an altitude airspeed rate of descent
the heading of the airplane
understand the wind and the weather in every few seconds being adjusting, constantly
so every week they would try to land the airplane at the end of the runway
bang
and week after week they did it
and surprise surprise
in less than six months
that team, was the best team in the bank!
they had gone from the worst money-losing unit
to the most profitable use it in the back
because they made their work visible
the team was given the responsibility to fix the problem
and they self-organized to make it happen
it's all about learning how to land the airplane
now from that banking experience I was asked by
a series of companies to come in and deal with tough problems
so I needed to figure out how to do this consistently and get other people to do it other than me I couldn't be there all the time for everyone
and so I began to think about how would I do this
I was running a little French company in Cambridge Massachusetts on the eye on the MIT campus
and five graduate students for MIT came by and they said
we're starting up a company building robots can you rent us some space
and I said sure, We have a couple of extra rooms you can use for a lab
and they were building these insect-like robots
and every other day
the robots would come wandering into my office
they were trying to hunt me down with heat-seeking sensors
and senior professor at MIT was a co-founder he would come by on Fridays, and he would
see how they were doing and I asked him I said
professor Brooks how do these robots work
he said Jeff: the first thing you understand
need to understand is that for 30 years
we've tried to build a smart system at MIT
and it's been a total failure
we tried to build this command and control system
with really big computers and huge databases
and it didn't work it
the best it could do was a smart chess program
so he said: I watched insects, and I wanted to create
something that had distributed intelligence
a chip in the leg that can move a leg
a chip in the spine that can coordinate legs
a neural network in the head
that figures out where to go
and he turned it on the legs flapped and it waddle to its feed was like a baby learning how to walk and three minutes was running around the room
I said wow that's amazing i used to have these really slow developers
maybe we could give them some simple rules
and they would learn how to boot up into a super-intelligent team do you think that work
and he said why don't you try it?
well I did a short time later
a company a very successful company hired me in to build a new product
that was going to replace all the rolled products at half the time they'd ever done it before
and I had to figure it out
and our product had to be used by really big companies
and I had to tell them how to use the product in an agile way
and we studied the literature
and we found the best paper in the Harvard Business Review
we're not gonna talk to you cheat two Japanese professors had
shown three different styles of leadership
number one: the Gantt chart
you know what happens with that one
number two a transitional strategy at Fuji xerox
and number three
that what they saw and the best manufacturing plants of the world
so we ran how to implement number three
and talking Tanaka said it needs to be self-organizing self-motivated teams
management needs to let go and step back
they need to get out of the way
so the teams can figure out what to do
so we implemented that in 1993 by 1995 I got together with my partner Ken Schwaber
we started rolling it out to industry
in 2001 we wrote the agile manifesto
and since then it's gone everywhere in the world
all the major software companies
they're building fighters
agricultural machinery, space probes
Joe justice in the picture there is showing a car company
how to build a car in one week cycles
a new car every week
but the leading edge of this agile movement today
is actually in the schools of the US and Europe
I recently visited a school in the Netherlands
where the kids have been trained
to self learn
the bell would ring they'd come running into the room
tease of four they would run to the wall put up their scrum boards of the wall
they'd have a short daily meeting what did we do yesterday what would we do today
what are the problems that are getting in the way
run to the desk and start to work
the teachers just standing there saying nothing
they only talk when they're asked for help
the enthusiasm of these kids
was so overwhelming I'm standing there with other teachers we're crying
the kids say it's faster learning better grades they finish weeks early they have more fun
there's a definition of fun for everything they do they make sure it's achieved
the handicapped children are involved naturally in the workings of the teams as team members
the motivation problems go away
the disciplinary problems go away
the team execute self-discipline
if they need a little help from the teacher they might ask for it but generally they don't need it
so this is the future of learning
and if you go back into the world that most of us live in
we're not operating that way
the surveys show that most people think work really sucks
the only thing worse at work is being sick in bed
I recently asked a software developer for working on BMW software in Paris
how he liked his scrum team
he started choking up he started bursting into tears he said
I can't tell you the acceleration I feel it's changed my life
every one of you could experience that
you could grab back your power
grab back your freedom
gain a life that's transcendent
and the xhilaration you would feel would give you an a happiness
that you would remember till your grave
that's what I wish for every person in this room
and you need to give up and let go to make it happen
thank you very much