sprint planning is the longest of the
scrum meetings depending on sprint
length some teams will take as long as a
full day and standard scrum advice is to
spend up to two hours per week of the
sprint so from two hours to plan a
one-week sprint up to eight hours to
plan a four week sprint unfortunately
some teams turn sprint planning into a
marathon lasting even longer than this
sprint planning should never take longer
than a day and I find that even the
advice of two hours per week of the
sprint is too much for a good
experienced team a good experienced team
should strive to finish sprint planning
in much closer to just one hour per week
of the sprint so a two-hour meeting for
a two-week sprint and a four-hour
meeting for a four week sprint there are
two general reasons why sprint planning
can turn into a marathon one lack of
preparation to trying too hard to get it
perfect the first of these a lack of
preparation is the results of not
properly maintaining the product backlog
a product backlog needs maintenance care
and feeding if you will you can spend
either a little time on the product
backlog each sprint or you can spend a
lot of time during one sprint when you
discover the backlog is a mess and is
not well understood the type of
maintenance I'm referring to here often
called product backlog grooming or
refinement is the subject of its own
video in this course the problem with
not being prepared for sprint planning
is that the meeting will take a long
time because the team will have a lot of
questions for the product owner I've
actually seen teams in this situation
spend a week on sprint planning one team
I'm thinking about started the sprint
planning meeting on Monday morning in
this meeting it was clear that this was
the first time that the team had heard
of many of the product backlog items and
that many were quite large after a few
hours together the team and product
owner decided to end the meeting and
spend the next few days working to
understand the top handful of product
backlog items they agreed to reconvene
on Friday to finish sprint planning this
team would have been far better off
spreading that time across the
proceedings sprinter to so that it could
have come in to sprint planning better
prepared the other reason why sprint
planning can turn into a marathon is
that a team is trying too hard to get
sprint planning perfect there's no need
to be perfect in fact there's an optimal
amount of time to spend in sprint
planning here we see a graph showing how
well a sprint is planned based on how
much time is spent in the sprint
planning meeting spend too little and
the Sprint will be poorly planned this
will also lead to the wrong amount of
work being brought into the sprint
either too much or too little and that
will lead to problems during the sprint
spending too much time in a sprint
planning meeting however is just as
inefficient going into too much detail
with each product backlog item or trying
to estimate - precisely waste the time
of all team members without adding value
to the sprint the goal is to be right
here in the optimal area imagine this
scenario as a scrum master you run a
sprint planning meeting as you normally
would at the end of the meeting you have
a sprint backlog a set of tasks and an
estimate to go with each task but you
know the team didn't think of everything
so you tell them to stay in the room for
another hour just silently thinking as
hard as they can at the end of the hour
you ask what they came up with together
they've identified another five tasks
that's great you think the Sprint is now
better planned but you know it's still
not perfect so you ask them to sit there
and think for another hour but this time
you pump in some Mozart music after all
he's supposed to make us think better at
the end of that hour you ask the team
members what they came up with and they
give you another four tasks again the
Sprint is now better planned but at what
cost
you've kept the team walked up another
two hours I contend that's not worth it
perfect sprint planning does not mean
the team has thought of every task
perfect sprint planning means the team
has perfectly figured out what set of
product backlog items they can do during
the sprint think about that for a moment
and let it sink in being perfect is not
thinking of every task being perfect is
knowing the right set of product backlog
items that can be delivered in a sprint
to
do that the team does not need to think
of every task they need to think of the
big things but not everything in my
experience a team doing a good job of
sprint planning will identify only about
two-thirds of all the tasks its members
will do during the sprint in other words
the team leaves the meeting having
failed to identify about one-third of
all the tasks that will be done during
the sprint and I contend this is a good
thing the team could stay longer and
identify more of the work but it's not
worth the extra time now notice I said
the team fails to identify one third of
the tasks not one third of the hours the
tasks that are not identified tend to be
the smaller tasks we don't miss the big
two dues just the little ones so the
number of hours of work not identified
will be less than a third if you're a
scrum master I encourage you to know the
percentage of tasks your team identifies
during sprint planning this is an easy
metric to collect simply count the
number of tasks identified during sprint
planning and then count the number of
tasks that have been identified by the
end of the Sprint divide and that will
tell you the percentage your team is
identifying during sprint planning if
you find your team's identifying more
than two-thirds during sprint planning
first congratulate them on doing such a
great job of identifying work that needs
to be done then try shortening their
sprint planning meetings they can
probably get by with spending a bit less
time in sprint planning on the other
hand if you do the math and find your
team is only identifying 50% of the
eventual tasks during sprint planning
your team will probably benefit from
spending a bit more time in the sprint
planning meeting the team is under
estimating the effort required to
complete the product backlog items which
means they are probably bringing in more
work than they can deliver there could
be other forces at work here causing the
team to be unable to identify a higher
percentage of tasks perhaps they aren't
adequately prepared for the sprint
planning meeting perhaps the product
owner is changing what's needed to
deliver the product backlog item perhaps
we don't have the right people
participating in the sprint planning
meeting but most often when a team
routinely identifies much less than two
the tasks needed that team will benefit
from spending a bit more time in sprint
planning sprint planning is designed to
help the team select the right set of
product backlog items to bring into the
sprint the team members should discuss
each item just enough to know how they
will implement it and therefore whether
or not they have enough bandwidth to
complete that item in this sprint the
right amount of time then is just enough
to correctly choose a set of product
backlog items that can be completed
during the sprint by knowing the
percentage of tasks your team identifies
during sprint planning and by remaining
focused on the true purpose of sprint
planning
selecting the right set of product
backlog items to bring into a sprint and
discussing them just enough to
successfully implement them you can help
your team find the right amount of time
it should spend in sprint planning