in this section we'll learn all about the Sprint review meeting
we will cover the input to the meeting
the goal
who attends
the time box
the general approach to running the meeting
and the output
the Sprint review meeting is held at the end of the Sprint
the primary input is the increment developed during the sprint
the goal of the meeting is to inspect that product increment and adapt the product backlog as needed
the attendees of the meeting are the scrum team
and any stakeholders invited to attend by the product owner
the time box for the Sprint review meeting is four hours for a one-month sprint
for shorter sprints the time box is typically shorter
and in practice most sprint planning meetings are completed well before the time box expires
the approach to the meeting is focused around three key areas
first the team demonstrates the product increment developed during the Sprint
the team answers any questions that might arise about the demonstrated increment
next the attendees have a collaborative discussion of the business context for the product
including any new developments in the marketplace, feedback from users ,
projected release dates if applicable and any other relevant details
that help the team decide what would be the most valuable thing to work on next
finally the product backlog is adapted based on the discussion
so that the scrum team enters the next sprint
with a shared understanding of the priority and context of their work
the output of the Sprint review then is a revised product backlog
that defines the probable product backlog items for the next sprint
some people incorrectly refer to the Sprint review as the sprint demo
notice that the demonstration of the working product increment is only a small portion of the sprint review meeting
while it covers an important aspect of the inspect step of an empirical process,
a demonstration alone does not cover the important adapt step of the Sprint review meeting