once the product owner has a product backlog,
that's useful for starting the sprint
he needs to meet with the team
before they go into planning for the sprint to look at the backlog, review it  and estimate its sizing
and in scrum we use relative sizing
and we often call them story points for use we measure the size of backlog items and points
once that's clear to the development team
then they're ready to start the first sprint with a sprint planning session
in that session they'll bring the product backlog in
the team will decide how much backlog they think they can implement
in a sprint which is often one week two weeks three weeks no more than four weeks
and they will pull from the back product backlog
that's one of the things that's very different from scrum
it's based on Lean principles where you pull into the system
nobody's pushing stuff on to the team
what the lean companies have found out is a push process slows things down
so the team pulls off of that backlog in sprint planning
they then will spend some time maybe breaking that backlog down into smaller pieces
and figuring out what they're what they're going to do
they may even take those small pieces and estimate how many hours it's going to take to implement them
so they can see you know do they have as much time as they need to to get done what they plan
and when they really have looked at that and they feel comfortable with it
then it's a responsibility of the team to commit to deliver that in the two weeks
and that kicks off the Sprint