the product backlog is the scrum
artifact that answers the question what
is most important to build next
the primary problem of economics applied
to product and service development is
that stakeholders have seemingly
unlimited wants but organizations have
limited means given that problem we need
to decide what order a scrum team or
group of scrum teams will address
stakeholder desires the product backlog
is an ordered list of everything that
might be needed in the product it makes
priorities transparent to all
stakeholders the product owner is the
scrum team member responsible for the
product backlog including what goes in
it
what order it is in and ensuring that it
is always available to stakeholders and
the team to provide transparency and to
aid the product owner in ordering
product backlog items have a description
an estimate and value
[Music]
a product backlog is a constantly
evolving artifact several sources of
information can change our understanding
of what should be built next including
but not limited to feedback on a
completed product increment at a sprint
review meeting feedback and ideas from
current and potential users and
customers ideas from internal
stakeholders including the development
team and emerging competitive and
technical opportunities multiple scrum
teams often work together on the same
product one product backlog is still
used to describe the upcoming work on
the product a product backlog attribute
that groups items may then be employed
with the dynamic nature of product
development the product backlog is
constantly being updated and refined
this is a scrum team activity led by the
product owner product backlog refinement
will be described in more detail in
another video