hi I'm Mike Cohn and I'd like to welcome
you to the scrum repair guide video
course this course came about because
when I was in my teens and early 20s I
owned a couple of old Volkswagen bugs
these were great cars fun to drive and
very affordable but driving any car
that's ten to twenty years old means you
have to be prepared to do some
maintenance this wasn't a problem on old
Volkswagens because the parts were cheap
and the cars were so easy to work on I'm
not mechanically inclined but the
engines of 1960s Volkswagens were so
simple even I could work on them but I
still needed some guidance on what to do
I was fortunate to have a friend who
loved old VW's even more than I did and
he was a wonderful resource just as good
was this book here how to keep your
Volkswagen alive a manual of step by
step procedures for the complete idiot
talk to nearly anyone who ever owned an
air-cooled Volkswagen and you'll find
they owned this book it was first
published in 1969 and has been through
nineteen editions with this book as my
inspiration I wanted to create a guide
to repairing the most common problems I
see on scrum teams so in this course
you'll see videos with advice on
improving teamwork like how to avoid the
problem of programmers handing code over
to testers with only two days left in
the sprint will cover how to overcome
common problems with stakeholders like
properly setting their expectations and
dealing with their desire to lock down
scope schedule and cost way too early in
a project I'll talk about some of the
problems that are common to scrum team
meetings things like sprint planning
taking way too long and the daily scrum
turned into a status meeting we'll look
at issues involving each of the roles on
a scrum project we'll discuss team
member behavior we'll look at things
your product owner could be doing better
we'll even look at things the scrum
master might be doing wrong and much
much more I don't expect that repairing
problems on a scrum team will ever be as
easy as repairing an old Volkswagen is
but I do hope that to
together we can make the results just as
rewarding