سلام. به آکادمی اجایل خوش آمدید
hi and welcome to the agile Academy
در این گفتگو از سری گفتارهای چابکی و تجربه
In this Agile in practice talk
we'd like to address how agile teams come up with a definition of done
that will help them to decide when the work is completed
For agile teams
done means that nothing more needs to be done, for a piece of work to be taken into production or go live
while agile teams come to an agreement on the definition of done
they will brainstorm what tasks need to be done
and what artifacts need to be produced to bring a single story or a piece of functionality into production
they will identify what can be done and what can't be done
they will also capture the blockers for the can't be done items
And then get consensus on what can be done items the
definition of done is important for agile teams to accurately measure the progress of their work
the whole team including their customer Jen the HR team leader
is involved in coming to a definition of done and they revisit irregularly to update it
here is Susan the business analyst of the team
she explains what the definition of done is to the team so they could get a shared understanding
essentially done means that the customer our product owner is happy with what the team has delivered
and has signed off and all the stories
however she continues
since the story goes through a development process, you can identify smaller checkpoints of done along the way
For example only after I have captured enough acceptance criteria and assumptions for a user story
can it be picked up by the developers
since all of this information doesn't fit on a story card
I capture them and what I like to call a narrative which is my artifact to express done
these might be a sketch of a feedback form
a prototype screen shot
and even some technical considerations
Tom the developer continues the explanation
in order to get a story closer to done
my piece of work has to be reviewed by another developer
and successfully integrated into the current version of the solution
Damien says
another checkpoint on the road to getting a story done
is that we have implemented the feedback of users
ensuring that a story meets user experience satisfaction
above all it means that Jen, as our customer and product owner
has tested the story and approved it
in fact a story is done when it passes all tests created based on the acceptance criteria Susan
our business analyst has captured
this will include performance tests
which means testing the response time of the system when a lot of people use it at the same time
that's our definition of done as developers
what about for you as a product owner Jen?
well Damian as a customer I'd say that the work is done when the employees over company
have an easy-to-use system
in which they can fill in and access performance feedback
bill sums up the team's discussion
So let's have a look at what we are come up with for our definition of done
whether it is a story
a feature, an iteration
or for a whole release of our product or a system
the work is done when we as a team
truly believe that we will not have to touch it again
in this agile and practice talk
you learned that agile teams come to consensus about what done means when the user definition to track the progress of their work
this progress is displayed in burnt charts
and agile metric that is a topic for another time