during sprint planning the scrum team
creates two outputs the Sprint goal and
the sprint backlog the Sprint goal is a
high level objective that provides
guidance to the development team on why
the work of that sprint is important it
could be a customer outcome a business
impact a learning goal a risk reduction
objective or or anything else that helps
the development team work cohesively
towards a shared goal rather than on
separate initiatives during the Sprint
the Sprint backlog can be thought of as
having two components the what of the
Sprint and the how of the Sprint during
sprint planning the development team
pulls the highest ordered items from the
product backlog into the sprint backlog
they pull as many items into the sprint
as they forecast can be delivered into a
done increment within the sprint time
box the completion of these items
enables the team to reach the Sprint
goal notice that pulling these items
into the Sprint will usually create the
need to do further product backlog
refinement during the Sprint so that
there are sufficient ready items for the
next sprint planning
the Sprint backlog also contains the
development teams plan for how they will
deliver the product increment and
realize the Sprint goal the Sprint
backlog makes visible all of the work
that the development team identifies as
necessary to meet the Sprint goal the
Sprint backlog should provide enough
detail that changes in progress can be
understood in the daily scrum the
development team modifies the Sprint
backlog throughout the Sprint as they
work through the plan and learn more
about the work needed to achieve the
Sprint goal potential modifications to
the Sprint backlog during the Sprint may
include adding newly discovered work
needed to meet the Sprint goal updating
estimates on the amount of work
remaining to reach the Sprint goal and
removing elements of the plan that are
discovered to be unnecessary only the
development team can change its Sprint
backlog during a sprint the Sprint
backlog is a highly visible real-time
picture of the work that the development
team plans to accomplish during the
Sprint and it belongs solely to the
development team