this definition is from the "SCRUM GUIDE"
the official document created and regulary updated by Scrum's co-creators:
Jeff Sutherland and Ken Schweiber
in this video, we will explain that definition
and describe the underlying theory of Scrum
Scrum is described as a process framework rather than a complete process for building products
one important distinction is that Scrum is intentionally incomplete
it does not specify all of the steps required to build a product
instead, It describes the framework within which a variety of processes and techniques can be deployed
the Scrum framework consists of Scrum teams
and their associated roles
events
and artifacts
each of these core-components has a few rules
and there are simple rules describing the relationship and interaction between the components
anything not described by those components and rules is not part of the framework
the Scrum team decides which processes and techniques to use within the framework
if the team orthe organization were to decide to remove or alter any of the components or their rules
they are no longer using Scrum
Scrum exists only in it's entirety
and each of the core-components and their associated rules serves a specific purpose
the second part of the definition, describes something called a "Complex Adaptive Problem"
to understand that, let's look at a spectrum
on one end of the spectrum we will place problems that are simple,predictable and static... or unchanging
on the other end, we will place problems that are complex, unpredictable and adaptive... or always changing
most professionals are familiar with how to address problems at the left end of this spectrum
since these are predictable problems, we are able to create a detailed plan
the plan might have many steps and dependencies
but, if the system is predictable, the plan will progress without any surprises or the need to change things along the way
this approach is known as "Defined Process Control"
which means that we define a specific process for every step along the way
this works well when things are predictable
when things are more complex and unpredictable
this approach is not very effective
one of the most frequently cited books on this topic is called:
process dynamics,modeling and control
by Babatunde A. Ogunnaike and W. Harman Ray
in this book the authors explain:
It is typical to adopt a defined approach
when underlying mechanisms by which a process operates are resonably well understood
when the process is too complicated for the defined approach, the empirical approach is the appropriate choice
Ogunnaike and Ray are telling us that the defined approach doesn't work when things are complex and adaptive
and that we should instead use something called:
Empirical Process Control
so let's explore what that means
an empirical approach is one that is based on observations and evidence
empiricism is the central idea behinde the scientific method
that we can find out what is true through experiments with concrete observable results
in order to make good observations, an empirical process has three pillars
transparency
inspection
and adaptation
Scrum is based on empirical process control
and so significant aspects of Scrum are designed to provide transparency,inspection and adaptation
to creat transparency, Scrums events and artifacts are visible to all of those responsible for their outcomes
organizations using Scrums, frequently inspect Scrum artifacts
and progress towards a sprint goal
to detect undesirable variances
they balance the frequency of the inspection, so it doesn't get in the way of the work
but still provides sufficient opportunities to course-correct
if during inspections, anything is determined to be outside of the goals of the effort,
the process,plans or product are adapted
the adaptation is made  as son as possible to optimize for a better outcome
to summarize:
Scrum is a lightweigh framework
made up of a few roles, events,artifacts and their rules that is simple to understand
however, since it relies on empirical process control to address complex adaptive problems,
it is difficult to master