The team is an extremely important concept in scrum
so let's start with the definition of that term
at the highest level
a team is any group of individuals
that work independently and collaboratively to accomplish a shared goal
let's delve into some of the key characteristics of a successful team ,
as defined by the great team expert J.Richard Hackman
the first characteristic is something that Hackman called a real team
Successful teams have clear membership boundaries ,
interdependence among the members ,
and at least moderate stability of membership over time
The second characteristic is compelling direction
Successful teams , have a compelling direction.
a purpose that is clear , challenging and consequential
and that focuses on the ends to be achieved
rather than the means the team must use in persuing them
Third is enabling structure
Successful teams have structures , tasks , composition ,
and core norms of conduct that enable rather than impede teamwork
Fourth , supportive context
Successful teams have structures and systems around them
that provide the resources and support
that members need to carry out their collective work
And fifth , competent coaching
Successful teams have competent coaching available
to help members get over rough spots
and take advantage of emerging opportunities
That coaching is provided at times in the team lifecycle ,
when members are most ready to receive and use it
If we take any of these characteristics away ,
the team starts to struggle to be effective
Scrum supports each one of this characteristics
First , Scrum asks organizations to creat real teams
by clearly defining team membership and roles
Second , the product backlog , product owner role and sprint goals ,
all help provide compelling direction for the scrum team
Third , Scrum is itself a set of enabling structures for how to do work within a team
Fourth , the role of management in an organization using scrum ,
shifts to providing supportive context for the scrum team
by removing organizational impediments
And fifth , the scrum master role is created
to provide ongoing competent coaching to the team
Scrum also specifies two characteristics for scrum teams :
Self organization and cross functionality
We will explore these two concepts later in this section