جلسه بازاندیشی اسپرینت، جلسه‌ جذابیه
now the retrospective is an interesting meeting
افراد دور هم جمع می‌شوند و با هم در این‌باره گفتگو می‌کنند که کارهای اسپرینت قبل چطور بوده
because people get together and they talk about well how did it go for the last sprint
و اولین کاری هم که باید انجام بشه اینه که فهرستی از رویدادهای گذشته تهیه کنند
and the first thing they need to do is really recollect what happened
البته یادآوری جزییات اتفاقاتی که در چند هفته اخیر رخ داده، کار سختیه
it's hard to people remember all the details of what's happened in the last couple of weeks
برای همین، معمولا فردی وجود داره که نمایی از این رویدادها رو به شکل بصری آماده می‌کنه
so often they'll have people maybe make it visual,
ممکنه چیزهایی را که در این چند هفته اتفاق افتاده، روی برگه‌های رنگی یادداشت کنه. حالا هر چقدر هم که اسپرینت طول کشیده باشه
maybe put things on sticky notes all the things that happened in the last few weeks however long the Sprint has
بعد از این، کارهایی رو که دوست داشتند از کارهایی که دوست نداشتند تفکیک می‌کنند
and then given that, picture what did they like and what didn't they like
زیرا آنچه را که دوست داشتند
because the things they like they want to keep
and the things they didn't like they want to figure out how to do differently
based on understanding that
the team will then come up with okay here's some process improvements we can make to make our sprint better
and they'll talk about prioritizing those
because it turns out that tuning an organization is very similar to tuning a computer
if your website is too slow
you don't want to try to fix everything at once
you want to identify where in that software that is there a bottleneck
where is the biggest bottleneck and you want to fix that first
when you fix it the whole system will change its dynamics
and the next bottleneck is often we you least expected it to be.
so it turns out you only want to fix one thing at a time
so the challenge for that retrospective is to figure out what is the one thing that if we fixed it
would have the biggest impact on making this team go fast
and then commit to fix it
so the whole point of the retrospective is identifying that one thing and getting a commitment
if that thing is not identified
and it's not fixed ideally before the next retrospective
then the retrospective has been a complete waste of time
and people will say why are we doing this? nothing's happening.
so the retrospective is designed to fix the most important thing
when that happens the team will accelerate
they'll start to go faster,
the quality of the product will go up
so the retrospective is critical to improving performance of teams