hi and welcome to the agile Academy
In this Agile in Practice talk
we'd like to show you how agile teams use story cards to capture user requirements
and to manage the delivery of user functionality
delivering a new employee performance review system for the HR department is a big piece of work
so the team want to chunk it down into smaller pieces
when agile teams capture requirements, they do so from a perspective of the user
hence we call the requirement user stories
they are retinal index cards which we then call story cards
Meet Susan, the business analyst of the team
she is having a conversation with our customer Jen
the HR team leader and product owner for the system, together
they are identifying some of the user stories
for example:
they have identified team leaders as users for the new system
one of the stories that Susan captures is:
as a team leader I need to see the performance reviews of my team members
so that I can have a conversation with them about their performance
Do you notice the structure that Susan is using?
"As a ..."
"I need ..."
"So that ..."
as a team leader refers back to the user who wants this piece of functionality
"I need", tells us what the user wants.
The "So That..." part, describes why the user wants it.
What benefit or value he or she expects to get out of it?
expressing the benefit is important in agile
since we want to deliver value to our customers fast with less risk
Susan and Jane also discuss acceptance criteria
these are the criteria that will let the team know when the story is done
Susan captures them in the key statement on the back of the story card
in short
a story card allows you to record a compelling story that tells you what the user wants and why
to collect all requirements of the new performance review system
Susan will have many more workshops with Jane and several potential users
in order to capture their stories
The team realized that a story card is too small to gather all the information
it's just enough to identify the requirement
we often say that a story card as a promise for a conversation
just before we start working on the story
we will come and talk with you to discuss the story in more detail
stories on the backlog
now that Susan has chunk down the work into smaller pieces, the team can start planning the work
Susan sticks a story card on the wall
so everyone can see them
great says Bill now we can prioritize and estimate the work
prioritizing and estimating the story cards
will help the team to set an order and the time-line, towards the total work.
Jane and the team are happy
the big piece of work is now chunk downed into smaller pieces of work
and put into a clear order
in this talk
you saw how agile team capture user stories with story cards
which they then use to prioritize and estimate their work
How agile teams exactly prioritize and estimate the work
is a topic for another time, and worth checking out on our website.