okay well the reason we have scrum is because I came into software development from a medical school
I dunno 11 years funded by the National Cancer dudes research on complex adaptive systems
and as a large banking company hired me to come in and help them with their advanced technologies
and as I looked at the way they were managing projects,
I realized developers were always late,
management was always under pressure, they were putting pressure on the developers
, the more pressure they would put on the developers, the later the project would get
and the whole thing was designed in such a way
that the stable state of the system was not what you wanted
in order to do that we had to change the whole dynamics
now what we knew from research at Bell Labs is that we had to have very few roles in the team that was doing software development
the specialized silos of activity slowed down communications and made it possible to
so one of the first things we did was we we set it up we only had a team and we had a team leader
we read a paper by two Japanese business school professors on the best teams in the world
and they described how the best product about new product development teams were set up how the teams were motivated
we set up the team just like that.
they the team wanted to know what we call the team leader. we call them the scrum master.
we then as we got the role simplified, we streamlined and leaned out all the system.
we very quickly found we needed a person we called the product owner in addition to the scrum master
who was responsible for clearly specifying the backlog in the right ordering
so when we shipped the product it would it would really take the market as a really good product
so we had the product owner the scrum master and the team
we then turned our attention to the meetings because in order to build software fast ,
you cannot have people to go into meetings all the time where they're wasting a lot of time
so we ask what are the minimal meetings we need to have four scrum
we knew we needed to deliver a software in short cycles
no more than four weeks probably the majority of the teams now are doing two-week sprints
so we needed a meeting at the beginning of the sprint to define okay
what is what it what are we going to pull from the product backlog owned by the product owner into that two-week cycle,
how are we going to implement it and and track it, a meeting at the beginning of the cycle
we also knew because again of research done by Bell Labs
that the highest performing teams were driven by daily meetings
so we knew we had to have a daily meeting but we wanted it to be a really short meeting and
and we got it down to no more than fifteen minutes
and in that meeting everybody on the team needs to know what everybody else has been doing, what they're going to do next
and how they can help one another move really fast
so it's like a huddle in a football game but a little bit longer than a huddle
at the end of the Sprint the model that we had when we started scrum,
I had worked near in a previous company near MIT with the Media Lab there and their motto was demo or die
so at the end of every sprint we were got a demo real working software ,
two people who would use the software and get their feedback ,
because it's the feedback cycle that tends to really make development go fast
so now we're down to three meetings a meeting at the beginning of the Sprint immediate at the end and a daily meeting in the middle
we then turned our attention to the reporting
because one of the problems with software development is they do a lot of reporting a lot of is in the form of Gantt charts
and the Gantt charts are always incorrect because the Gantt chart is made and then things change
and then the Gantt chart isn't correct anymore and so it's very hard to do planning by the Gantt chart
I looked at that and I said you know the problem with these teams finishing a two-week cycle on time
is similar to trying to land an aircraft on a runway, because for 11 years I have been a fighter pilot
so we Institute what I call the burndown chart ,
how fast is the team going, how much is left during the sprint before it touched down,
are they headed in the right direction and
just watching them trying to land that sprint  is the way we monitor it
we put that up in the wall so that scrum would be self reporting
if anybody wanted to see the state of the scrum they could go and look on the wall we didn't have to do reporting anymore
so on that wall has evolved into the product backlog we're working on any tasks
that we're implementing in the backlog, the burndown chart and as tasks are being worked on
,they're moving across the wall from needing to be done,they're in a working state and now they're done and tested
so now we had completely streamline, the rolls, the meetings and the reporting became self reporting
and that sets that set the stage for the really high performing teams
that we'd like to see with scrum