an increment broadly defined is an
increase or addition especially when
that addition represents one of several
steps in a sequence in scrum the
development team works to deliver a new
increment of the product every sprint
each increment is a new updated usable
version of the product so the product
owner may choose to immediately release
it a product increment is a tangible
output of each and every sprint the
increment is considered done if it can
be immediately released without any
additional work each increment is
additive to all prior increments and is
thoroughly tested ensuring that all
increments work together in order to
assess when work is complete on a
product backlog item or an increment the
scrum team creates a shared definition
of done this definition provides
transparency about the level of quality
that is considered sufficient to release
an increment the definition of done
guides the development team in knowing
how many product backlog items to
selecting sprint planning since the
purpose of each sprint is to deliver
increments of potentially releasable
functionality that adhere to the scrum
teams current definition of done this
definition will vary significantly per
scrum team since each team
collaboratively creates it based on
their own context and goals when
multiple scrum teams work on the same
system or product release they
collaborate to create a shared minimum
definition of done to which all teams
will adhere
you