for an individual team or organization to realize the benefits of scrum
the structural components of the framework  are an important but incomplete factor
the components of the framework are the visible logical system of scrum
since scrum is meant to be used by people
who have complex varied beliefs and values that influence their behavior
it is important to describe the values that make the system work in practice
the components of the framework are like the brain of scrum
the five scrum values commitment courage focus openness and respect are like the heart of scrum
commitment literally means joined together
it involves sharing our sincere intent to act
and then accepting responsibility for following through on that intended action
in scrum people personally commit to achieving the shared goals of the scrum team
courage means from the heart
it involves acting in alignment with our beliefs especially when that is hard
scrum team members have courage to do the right thing
and work on tough problems
focus comes from the Latin word for domestic hearth
which was the location of the fire at the center of the home
people in the home gathered around the hearth for warmth light and sustenance since it was used for cooking
the focus was literally the thing that brought people together
in scrum everyone focuses on the work of the sprint and the goals of the scrum team
openness means exposed or evident
the scrum team and its stakeholders agreed to be open about all the work
and the challenges with performing the work
openness is closely related to the empirical pillar of transparency
respect means to look or view again
respect involves taking a second look at how we view others
to develop a sincere appreciation for the unique capabilities that they contribute
scrum team members respect each other to be capable independent people
when these five values are embodied and lived by the scrum team
the structures become far more effective at their intended goal of empirical improvement
at the same time the structures are designed to encourage the development of the values
giving meaning and depth to the work
successful use of scrum depends on people developing a greater awareness and proficiency
at both the intelligence represented by the structural framework and the intension represented by the five values
both are important areas for inspection and adaptation by a scrum team