scrum defines three roles within the
scrum team
the product owner, the development team and the scrum master
the product owner is responsible for maximizing the value of the product and
the work of the development team
one of the primary ways the product owner
manages this work is through the product backlog
the product owner is accountable
for the order of the items in the product backlog
for ensuring that the
items are clearly understood
and that the product backlog is transparent to
the scrum team and other stakeholders in
the organization
the product owner can choose whether to manage the product
backlog on their own
or to involve the development team in the work however the
product owner remains accountable
the development team is responsible for
building the actual product increment
in this work the development team is
cross-functional & self-organizing and
while individuals often have specialized
skills or areas of focus
accountability belongs to the team as a whole
development teams tend to have between 3 and 9 team members
smaller than three may result in a skill gap that makes it difficult
to deliver potentially releasable increments during a sprint
larger than nine results in a level of
complexity that makes coordination self-organization and empirical
management difficult
the scrum master is responsible for ensuring that scrum is
understood and used skillfully by the scrum team
scrum masters do this by
acting as a guide to the organization on scrum theory practices and rules
the scrum master is often described as a servant leader role
this description means that the scrum master leads by
helping rather than coercing
it can also be viewed as a role that
serves through modeling and agile mindset and skillful use of the scrum
framework
the scrum master ensures that the product owner development team and
organization as a whole
understand how scrum can be used to help them accomplish and align their goals