so microservices have been talked about
a lot over the last year or so I see a
huge amount of stuff on Twitter and the
like talking about this topic it's
something I've been hearing about for a
good bit for a little bit longer last
two or three years various of my
colleagues and friends have been talking
about micro services and for me the
struggle was to try and figure out well
what exactly are they what what do
people really mean when they talk about
microservices and also you know when
should we consider using this technique
is it new or not do we use it do we not
use it and what nerf is it in the first
place I mean the basic idea is fairly
straightforward you contrast it with
what's considered to be a traditional
place I mean the basic idea is fairly
straightforward you contrast it with
what's considered to be a traditional
monolithic application a monolithic a
monolithic application means you've got
various capabilities various things that
you want to provide and you put them all
in the same application typically
running in a single process and you
think of it as one thing the micro
service approach and its crew
disciplines is trying to take each of
these capabilities and put them into
separate processes and instead of having
one process have this network of
communicating processes a lot of people
like to use the example of of the UNIX
command line where if you want to get a
list of all the files in your directory
sorted you might use two or three
different programs put together in a
pipeline to do so it also has a
consequence for distribution if you've
got a model if you scale by effectively
cookie cutter in the monolith and
putting it on multiple machines while
we're microservices you've got more of a
flexible approach because you can put
different services on different machines
so that if some services get more load
than others they can have more copies of
them made that's the kind of very crude
overview but this is still a long way
away from what I would really call the
definition of it I mean
how does this vary from everything I've
been hearing people Yammer on about
definition of it I mean
how does this vary from everything I've
been hearing people Yammer on about
service-oriented architecture for the
last 10 years but the trouble is with
something like a topic like micro
services it's very hard to come up with
any kind of firm definition yes I mean
I've filled the same thing with no
sequel right I mean no sequel databases
I mean what's the definition and no
sequel and even further back I mean you
know what is the definition we come up
with really solid definition for
functional programming well you know
there are plenty out there you can
choose from quite a wide range what I
think is better to think about is
there are plenty out there you can
choose from quite a wide range what I
think is better to think about is
instead of thinking about a definition
to talk about common characteristics and
what I mean by common characteristics is
instead of thinking about a definition
to talk about common characteristics and
what I mean by common characteristics is
to say if you burnt the talk to AB whole
bunch of people doing micro-services and
you look for the common things that most
of them are doing your test is that most
people who say they're doing
micro-services should be doing most of
these things and I got together with one
of my colleagues who's one of these guys
has done a lot of work with micro
services and we came up with an article
that we published earlier this year
those of you at the back are going to
services and we came up with an article
that we published earlier this year
those of you at the back are going to
struggle with all that everything on the
slides that's at the bottom because of
the way the things laid out but it's out
there and I'm just going to summarize
some of these these were the nine common
characteristics that we came up with in
writing that article and I'm not going
some of these these were the nine common
characteristics that we came up with in
writing that article and I'm not going
to talk through them all because I don't
have enough time but I will highlight
some that I think are particularly
interesting so the first thing is this
notion of componentization via services
some that I think are particularly
interesting so the first thing is this
notion of componentization via services
now the idea software should be broken
up into components has been around again
forever we always a lot of people have
talked about component based software
and how it would be good to have
components that you can work with but
often the term component of course has
had a lot of problems in terms of
definition as well I remember a one
point object being substituted for
components and then components came back
definition as well I remember a one
point object being substituted for
components and then components came back
to objects again and it all got very
confusing what I focus on for a
definition of component really comes
from Ralph Johnson he said that what
we're trying to do is we're trying to
build software the way people would
from Ralph Johnson he said that what
we're trying to do is we're trying to
build software the way people would
assemble stereo
components you know you have an
amplifier you have speakers you have a
CD play have a tape player you can
replace any of these items independently
that's a crucial thing and indeed you
can upgrade any of these items
independently so if I want to get an
improved amplifier I don't have to
change everything else that's a goal of
independently so if I want to get an
improved amplifier I don't have to
change everything else that's a goal of
what we're aiming for a component is
something that's independently
replaceable independently upgradable so
in terms of software and we see
components to becoming two forms we
obtain libraries that we use from third
parties and we make them part of our
process and to some extent we have then
the choice of when do we want to upgrade
that do we want to get a new version of
our XML processing library or do we
stick with the one that we've currently
got and hopefully the upgrade isn't
going to affect the rest of our
stick with the one that we've currently
got and hopefully the upgrade isn't
going to affect the rest of our
application too much depending upon how
the dependences are all laid out a
service is a different kind of component
where it's running in its own process
the dependences are all laid out a
service is a different kind of component
where it's running in its own process
and while with a library we talk using
the language communication facilities
that we have built into whatever
language we're using with a service
the language communication facilities
that we have built into whatever
language we're using with a service
we're typically using inter process
communication facilities such as web
service calls or messaging or something
of that kind and the services give us
some useful advantages even when it
tends to replace ability and upgrade
ability if I've got a monolith with
components that are libraries and I've
got you know somebody brings out a new
version of a component that would be
really nice but it only works on Java 8
and I've got another component in my
monolith that doesn't work with Java 8
and can only work with Java 7 what do I
do I'm stuck but on the other hand with
if they were separate services they
would be running in completely different
runtimes and they could operate they
could be upgraded more independently now
there's a cost of course with that but
that's part of the notion of how it ties
into the independent upgrade ability so
for the next one
that's part of the notion of how it ties
into the independent upgrade ability so
for the next one
organization in around business
capabilities is another important theme
in the micro services view of the world
so a lot of lot even development
organizations organize themselves around
technology I mean you'll see this in a
lot of big companies I'll have their D
bas and their database group that might
have a completely different group of
people on the UI it's focused around
technology the key thing with the micro
have a completely different group of
people on the UI it's focused around
technology the key thing with the micro
services view of the world is that we
should instead organize around business
capabilities and that each team should
have some elements right the way through
and ideally focusing directly on the end
users themselves there's an interesting
have some elements right the way through
and ideally focusing directly on the end
users themselves there's an interesting
example of this from Amazon which is a
common certainly inspiration for the
micro services community where when they
divided everybody knows Amazon divided
themselves up into two pizza teams and
that's talked about a lot but what's
talked about a lot less often is the
fact that each team was responsible for
the communication right way through to
the end user experience and the idea
that that should connect right the way
through to the people at the end and
the end user experience and the idea
that that should connect right the way
through to the people at the end and
they should be judged on how does this
affect business outcomes right the way
through is a very important part of that
thinking so we have this notion of
divide yourself up around some kind of
business organization and make that as
full stack as possible perhaps when it
comes to comparison to what a lot of
people have come across in terms of
services one of the biggest shifts is
this shift about let's have smart
endpoints and dumb pipes when a lot of
people talk about service-oriented
architecture they talk about the idea of
let's get some powerful piece of
middleware that will automatically do
all sorts of stuff it'll route messages
it will apply business rules it does all
sorts of things this of course is the
the ESB the Enterprise Service bus or is
it more correctly known the egregious
spaghetti box
the micro-service community very much
regret reject this notion and says the
smarts instead should move to the
the micro-service community very much
regret reject this notion and says the
smarts instead should move to the
endpoints themselves what we want is
everything to connect together and to be
able to easily route messages or
communications between them but it
should be up to the endpoints where all
that smartness goes any business logic
any routing stuff all of this should be
based on the endpoints just give us a
good efficient piping mechanism and the
inspiration in many ways is of course
the Internet itself which works very
well because of the fact that it needs a
relatively dumb set of pipes and puts
all the intelligence onto the endpoints
another thing that also brings out this
variation to a lot of service stuff is
the notion of decentralization
decentralization in terms of the overall
way in which a service landscape is
the notion of decentralization
decentralization in terms of the overall
way in which a service landscape is
governed and in particularly
decentralization in terms of data
management so again if we think of the
the monolithic world we think of the
fact that generally all of the data is
sitting in one honking big relational
database all right and it's often can be
to write across a company you know our
company's standard is Oracle or our
company's standard is db2 everything
goes in the same place and even a lot of
service-oriented architectures it's
really a lot about multiple services or
pulling data in and out of one logically
large database the micro service appoint
point of view is to say now every
service should be responsible for its
own data and its own persistence again
point of view is to say now every
service should be responsible for its
own data and its own persistence again
this is another thing that is inspired
by the Amazon experience Amazon made
that one of their rules when they
shifted to a service-oriented approach
and said you may never talk to another
services data store you can only talk to
another service through its API and
that's the rule that the micro service
people push as well now this is a couple
advantages first it removes this
horrible mess of integrating through a
database which causes no end of problems
in enterprises all over the place the
second thing it does it frees up
individual services to use a datastore
that make
sense to them some services a relational
database will make sense
others would want to use one of these
sense to them some services a relational
database will make sense
others would want to use one of these
hot new no sequel fancy things and in
which case they use it for that but the
idea is yours choice of data persistence
should be entirely up to the individual
service themselves and that's part of
this general notion as I said of
decentralization it also goes to the
point of things like languages and tools
should again be individually chosen by
different service groups to make all of
this work it's really important to have
infrastructure automation so a lot of
things such as continuous delivery
techniques like Bluegreen deployment
that allow you to put stuff to live with
zero downtime these kinds of things are
mandatory in too in order to get this
kind of stuff to work because you're
talking about building what would be one
mandatory in too in order to get this
kind of stuff to work because you're
talking about building what would be one
application as a dozen or two dozen
services so it's very important you have
a very automated way of getting these
things going you also want to be able to
get new boxes and spin them up rapidly
it also puts a lot of emphasis on
things going you also want to be able to
get new boxes and spin them up rapidly
it also puts a lot of emphasis on
monitoring as well you've got to have
good monitoring so that when things go
wrong you can easily spot the fact that
monitoring as well you've got to have
good monitoring so that when things go
wrong you can easily spot the fact that
something's gone wrong and you can use
the monitoring tools to help you debug
it and that of course then leads into
the notion that you have this explicit
design for failure if you're going to
have remote services they're going to
fail particularly as you distribute them
across multiple nodes so this is another
part of the reason why monitoring is so
fail particularly as you distribute them
across multiple nodes so this is another
part of the reason why monitoring is so
important and of course it it's most
famous level you have things like the
chaos monkey Netflix is one of the most
well known MA micro service
architectures and they built a tool that
goes around randomly destroying nodes
and they use that in order to detect how
resilient their overall network is I
mean I don't run it all the time they
run it during office hours when there's
somebody there to fix things up but the
fact that you've got a tool that
deliberately causes failure in order to
help make sure you're resilient I think
it encapsulate svelt the attitude that
the micro service people have
and of course this is essential in any
kind of distributed system you have to
assume things are going to break so that
was our set of common characteristics
and I hope gives you a bit of a flavor
for the kinds of things that people talk
about but it still raises a number of
questions of which one of the biggest
things is is this really
service-oriented architecture is this
just the same kind of stuff that we've
been hearing about for a long time in
the context of SOA but in order to
answer that question you have to say to
yourself well what is SLA in the first
place and that is really I think at the
heart of the problem because I've heard
SLA defined in many different ways in
place and that is really I think at the
heart of the problem because I've heard
SLA defined in many different ways in
many different incompatible ways by
different people for some people SLA is
exactly what we've been talking about in
the micro service world and that's why I
met a number of people in the SOA
community a really ticked off at the
micro service people because their
attitude is well we've been doing all of
this and calling it SOA for years why do
you invent this new term and bring it
along what what is are you just calling
words because everybody knows of course
we become incredibly rich by coining
terminology I wish but of course SOA
means different things to different
people to many people in the micro
services community they've been around
big enterprises and to them SOA means
the enterprise service bus
it means Committees of people who are
there to lay down standards the health
services supposed to connect to each
other it's a very different world indeed
so the way I tend to think of it is
services supposed to connect to each
other it's a very different world indeed
so the way I tend to think of it is
saying well SOA is this very broad term
and microservices is a subset of its
usage and the value of the term micro
services is it allows to put a label on
and microservices is a subset of its
usage and the value of the term micro
services is it allows to put a label on
a useful subset of the SOA terminology
in my view the SOA term is too broad I
mean it means so many different things
it's practically meaningless but the
value of micro services is it carves out
a cut and consistent space within that
but he is perfectly fair to say that the
micro service approach has been done by
people under the name of SOA for at
least a decade
micro service approach has been done by
people under the name of SOA for at
least a decade
if not more
so it's not a new technique at all and
it's perfectly reasonable that people
are annoyed about it when they say Oh
micro services are nothing new that's a
perfectly reasonable response now one of
the problems with micro-services as a
term and I like to stress I didn't come
up with this term right I would have
come up with a better term but one of
the things about micro-services as a
term is that has this implication of
size and of course as soon as you say
the things about micro-services as a
term is that has this implication of
size and of course as soon as you say
micro is that well how big is a micro
service and you actually talk to any of
these people in the micro service world
and they're always very reluctant to
service and you actually talk to any of
these people in the micro service world
and they're always very reluctant to
answer this question they always say
these people in the micro service world
and they're always very reluctant to
answer this question they always say
well you know it should be one
responsibility that's a kind of bogus
thing to say right I can imagine payroll
being one responsibility and I know
that's a pretty big system right I mean
thing to say right I can imagine payroll
being one responsibility and I know
that's a pretty big system right I mean
it's all size I mean it's very
being one responsibility and I know
that's a pretty big system right I mean
it's all size I mean it's very
responsibilities are very flexible right
james lewis has this statement he says
mirco services have got to be small
enough to fit in my head now James has
config rate deal in his head as it turns
out but his point is of course the
survey that if you've got a service it
should be understandable to a single
person that's his test for it but that's
survey that if you've got a service it
should be understandable to a single
person that's his test for it but that's
still a bit vague I started asking
around people trying to get a sense of
size people were extremely reluctant in
many ways but the way I was able to get
some figure by saying well how many
size people were extremely reluctant in
many ways but the way I was able to get
some figure by saying well how many
people per service in your application
and I got a lot of different answers and
as you can see there's quite a spread
here now 15 people 10 services for
people 200 services there's quite a
range of different sizes it's certainly
here now 15 people 10 services for
people 200 services there's quite a
range of different sizes it's certainly
true that pretty where everywhere I come
across the notion of the to pizza team
from Amazon is fairly well regarded the
sense that you should never have a team
that's bigger than you could feed with
two pizzas I should say of course this
is two American pizzas and you can feed
a hell of a lot of people with two
American pizzas but I think the notion
is still there but within
there's still a lot of variability so
that's the best I can do when it comes
to defining microservices for you it's
still I'm afraid pretty fuzzy but you
know that's the way things go I think
however it is it does carve out a
reasonable class of systems the next
question of course is when you should
however it is it does carve out a
reasonable class of systems the next
question of course is when you should
use it what are the advantages of
micro-services compared to monoliths now
one big advantage of a monolith is it a
use it what are the advantages of
micro-services compared to monoliths now
one big advantage of a monolith is it a
relatively simple and familiar approach
to use and this is not to be
underestimated I mean I've already
started hearing and trickling in stories
of projects that you know decide you
know we want to use this micro-service
stuff because it's so cool we want to do
it and they ended up getting themselves
into trouble where they really should
have built a simple model if instead now
if you look at an application and you
say yeah that would work really nicely
as a simple rails app you don't want to
build start building it as a micro
say yeah that would work really nicely
as a simple rails app you don't want to
build start building it as a micro
service because micro services
introduced distributed computing they
often introduced asynchronous
communication and those are significant
introduced distributed computing they
often introduced asynchronous
communication and those are significant
complexity boosters so the monolith
still has the advantage of up to a
certain size at least simplicity one of
the great advantages of micro services
is the ability to deploy the various
pieces independently if you want to
upgrade a monolith you've got to upgrade
the whole thing I heard the story of an
insurance company where they've got one
monolith that handled all their
different lines of insurance if they
wanted to in to upgrade their auto
insurance they had to upgrade the home
insurance as well they couldn't do them
independently and that's a disadvantage
of a monolith you're forced to upgrade
all at once now if you're really good at
your continuous delivery pipelines I
think you can make that work but you but
it's much harder than trying to upgrade
and the separate pieces and that was in
fact one of the crucial reasons why
Netflix went down this route they had
difficulties getting their systems being
able to deploy as rapidly as they need
to do so they found that switching to a
micro service approach gave them more
flexibility and this is of course very
important in
in an age where we need to be able to
deploy new applications not once every
few months but every week every day and
in an age where we need to be able to
deploy new applications not once every
few months but every week every day and
often many times a day and then we are
granted your micro services that can
give you a greater degree of
availability if your recommendation
service goes down for some reason you
can still run your shopping cart and
this is important because what is the
most important thing to Americans
shopping right so nothing must stop the
shopping now that availability of course
comes from being handled be able to
handle failure effectively but if you've
got availability what does that mean you
comes from being handled be able to
handle failure effectively but if you've
got availability what does that mean you
lose consistency it's much harder to
maintain consistency with micro service
applications so you embrace eventual
consistency which may or may not be a
good thing depending on what where you
are and it's particularly difficult of
course to get the right kind of
consistent behavior so that I can
actually post an update when interacting
with a web app and actually make sure
consistent behavior so that I can
actually post an update when interacting
with a web app and actually make sure
that I see it and not go where did that
actually post an update when interacting
with a web app and actually make sure
that I see it and not go where did that
go did it get lost which is the kind of
thing that goes wrong when you don't do
consistency well another big issue we've
modeled with the monolith is that it
makes it relatively easy to refactor
particularly between modules now with
any kind of software design you want
good modularity you want to divide your
software up into pieces so that in order
to make a change I don't have to
understand the whole system I can just
understand one or two modules but that
means you've got to get your module
boundaries right and if you don't get
your module boundaries right you've got
to be able to change them now if you've
boundaries right and if you don't get
your module boundaries right you've got
to be able to change them now if you've
got a model if that kind of thing isn't
too bad you can say oh I need to move
this object from over here in that
module over there it's not a hard
refactoring to do in a microservices
world that becomes a hell of a lot
module over there it's not a hard
refactoring to do in a microservices
world that becomes a hell of a lot
harder because now you're talking about
refactoring to do in a microservices
world that becomes a hell of a lot
harder because now you're talking about
these remote calls so that's also I
think one of the problems with running
to monitor micro services too quickly if
you don't understand the module
boundaries well you've very easy to get
a lock yourself into a pure design and
you don't understand the module
boundaries well you've very easy to get
a lock yourself into a pure design and
anumana lift can be a good way of
figuring out
module boundaries are before you
anumana lift can be a good way of
figuring out
module boundaries are before you
actually do the split and we said that
one of the interesting things about
microservices is that they actually help
you preserve modularity a lot of people
you know like me waffle on endlessly
about how important it is to have good
modules now follow bob Martin's rules
about clean dependencies and all the
rest of it but the reality is most
systems find it hard to do it in
practice it's too easy to kind of do
little end runs around and expose little
things and not keep your module
boundaries solid on the other hand in a
micro service world your communications
things and not keep your module
boundaries solid on the other hand in a
micro service world your communications
are purely through your network
interfaces and it's maintained it makes
it really easy to ensure you don't share
mutable state which is of course one of
the best ways to get yourself into a
confusion in a monolith module
architecture so in many ways micro
service is kind of a discipline that
forces you to keep your modularity
architecture so in many ways micro
service is kind of a discipline that
forces you to keep your modularity
together and then I mean the last big
service is kind of a discipline that
forces you to keep your modularity
together and then I mean the last big
advantage in micro services they allow
you to go with multiple platforms if
some parts of your application stack are
best off with a traditional you know
Java whatever language you can use them
in some places and then you use sort or
an even experiment with say a closure on
other areas you've got the flexibility
now of course you don't necessarily want
to go so mad that you've got 20 services
written in 30 programming languages but
on the other hand that flexibility can
be very valuable just as you don't know
use JavaScript that's the one thing I
really don't want anybody to do
you've got to fight back against that
monster somehow so that's the trade-offs
microservices are not straightforward
you've got to fight back against that
monster somehow so that's the trade-offs
microservices are not straightforward
route to go in many ways I'd say if
you're not sure if you've got a
relatively small system don't worry
route to go in many ways I'd say if
you're not sure if you've got a
relatively small system don't worry
about it but on the other hand they can
you're not sure if you've got a
relatively small system don't worry
about it but on the other hand they can
be an appropriate appropriate
architecture in a lot of places and
we're still trying to understand what
the boundaries are between them it's
architecture in a lot of places and
we're still trying to understand what
the boundaries are between them it's
still fairly early and then the last
point I want to say is if you're going
to go down the micro-service point there
are certain things you've got to make
sure that you get sorted out otherwise
you're going to get into a lot of
trouble you've got to make sure that you
can provision new machines rapidly if
you're going to get into a lot of
trouble you've got to make sure that you
can provision new machines rapidly if
you're in a situation where it takes you
a month to get a new server set up and
provisioned and ready for use you're
going to have a lot of problems in the
micro service world this is of course
provisioned and ready for use you're
going to have a lot of problems in the
micro service world this is of course
why micro services go very nicely with
cloud if you can provision a new machine
in the cloud very quickly which is for
instance what Netflix do then that
cloud if you can provision a new machine
in the cloud very quickly which is for
instance what Netflix do then that
allows you a lot of flexibility there
make sure you have at least the basics
of monitoring you want to know when any
allows you a lot of flexibility there
make sure you have at least the basics
of monitoring you want to know when any
of your services go down you want to
know if something becomes unresponsive
or if important interactions or
transactions are getting dropped on the
floor you've got to have at least a
or if important interactions or
transactions are getting dropped on the
floor you've got to have at least a
basic level of monitoring in place
and also you've got to make sure that
your services can be automatically and
rapidly deployed um you don't want to be
spending two days deploying the service
it's got to be there in hours at the
very least and preferably minutes and it
should be as much as possible automatic
it's got to be there in hours at the
very least and preferably minutes and it
should be as much as possible automatic
process that's just the basics that's
just for running with just a couple of
certain amount of services and to do
more you've got to add more there's a
whole bunch of other stuff that you've
certain amount of services and to do
more you've got to add more there's a
whole bunch of other stuff that you've
got to get into play as well so make
sure you've at least got those basics on
the one I missed
DevOps culture that is you've got to
break down the barriers between the
operations group in the applications
group so that they're working together
if you've got a difficult communications
between the two again you're not going
to be able to manage the quantity of
services that you've got to deal with so
as I said those I think are the minimum
things to have when you first go
five you don't necessarily have to have
as I said those I think are the minimum
things to have when you first go
five you don't necessarily have to have
them when you start building but you
definitely have to have them when you go
live with this thing
so that's microservices a very brief
introduction I've written various things
on it there's tons of stuff out there on
the web you can go and find out more and
that's the end of my first talk
you