in archaeology the term artifact refers
to an object that was made by a human
the Latin roots of the word artifact
roughly translate to work of art so an
artifact is something that we make
either a tool that solves a problem or a
work of art that inspires scrum
describes three primary artifacts the
product backlog the Sprint backlog and
the product increment the product
backlog and sprint backlog describe work
to be done that will add value and the
product increment is the done portion of
the product completed during a sprint
the three scrum artifacts share the same
goals to maximize transparency and
promote a shared understanding of the
work the product backlog is the ordered
list of everything we might want the
development team to work on related to
the product under development
having a single ordered list makes
organizational priorities transparent to
all internal stakeholders of the product
a single product owner is responsible
for the ordering of the product backlog
which provides transparency to the
organization about the decision making
process used to arrive at the order the
product backlog is a dynamic artifact
meaning that it is constantly evolving
based on what is known at a given point
in time
the product owner collaborates with the
development team to refine the product
backlog product backlog refinement is an
ongoing activity that can require up to
10 percent of the development teams time
this dynamic ongoing and collaborative
refinement of the product backlog
promotes a shared understanding of the
work the Sprint backlog is
collaboratively created during sprint
planning by the development team
it is their plan for how they will
deliver the Sprint goal and related
product backlog items during the current
sprint it is regularly updated
throughout the Sprint as the development
team learns more it is a transparent
real-time picture of all of the work in
the current sprint the product increment
is the sum of all completed product
backlog items in a given Sprint plus the
value of previous increments the product
increment provides an accurate
transparent picture of the state of the
product at the end of each sprint
it helps scrum teams realize the agile
principle that working software is the
primary measure of progress which can be
rephrased as working product is the
primary measure of progress for non
software uses of scrum since the product
increment meets the team's definition of
done it is usable by stakeholders
providing an opportunity for inspection
of the current state of the product to
the extent that scrum artifacts are
completely transparent and have shared
understanding good decisions can be made
through inspecting and adapting in
complete transparency can lead to flawed
decisions reduced value delivery and
increased risk for this reason the scrum
master focuses on increasing
transparency of the scrum artifacts