in this section we'll learn about the
Sprint retrospective meeting we will
cover the goal who attends the time box
and the general approach to running the
meeting the Sprint retrospective meeting
is the final event of the Sprint held
after the Sprint review meeting the
Sprint retrospective is one of the most
important parts of scrum when done well
it enables the scrum team to
continuously improve their approach to
their work sprint after Sprint the goal
of the meeting is to inspect and adapt
the scrum teams approach to their work
and all members of the scrum team attend
the time box for the Sprint is three
hours for a one month sprint for shorter
Sprint's the time box is typically
shorter there are many effective
patterns to approach running the Sprint
retrospective meeting three elements are
common across most of these patterns
first the team inspects how the work was
completed in the last sprint focusing on
areas such as people relationships
process and tools next the attendees
have a collaborative discussion to
identify and order major items that went
well and opportunities for improvement
finally the team creates a plan for how
they will roll out any chosen
improvements the plan should be specific
so that improvements are actually
carried out in the next sprint a planned
improvement that is not carried out does
not help the team teams that are new to
scrum often focus largely on
improvements within the team itself as
improvements are made over multiple
sprints the scrum team reaches a level
of internal effectiveness such that the
largest opportunities for improvement
shift to how the scrum team interacts
with the broader organizational system
by constantly focusing sprint after
Sprint on the largest opportunities to
improve effective scrum teams
a larger and larger impact on the
effectiveness of the overall
organization