п«пе
so let's talk about how to pull all these ideas together
into an estimating approach that works
the technique is called planning poker
and it's loosely based on the Delphi and Wideband Delphi approaches
the date back to the RAND Corporation in the 1940s
in planning poker each estimator which should be everybody on the team
is holding a set of cards that contain the numbers the team has agreed to use as their estimates
normally this will be the modified Fibonacci sequence
but that's really up to the team
the product owner reads a product backlog item usually a user story to the team
the team in the product owner discussed the item team
team members asked questions
the product owner clarifies expectations
this can be as short as a few seconds
but it can take as long as needed
once each team member has decided upon an estimate
they pulled that card out of their hand
holding it so no one else can see it
when everyone has picked an estimate
the cards are revealed all at the same time
if everyone is holding up the same number we're done
write that number down as the estimate and move on
but if the numbers are different
we discuss it and an estimated again
let's see an example
during the first round our estimators hold up a 3, 8 a 2 and a 5
at this point I really want to hear from the others
why 8 why 2?
anybody can talk
but in this case I would really want to hear from Vadim and Ann
buddy might say well I'm the tester on this project and this is going to be really hard to test
I need to build a new test framework and so on
Ann says well Vadim is right
my two is too low I'm going to come up
but I've programmed this type of thing before and it's not that hard
so I'm coming up but not all the way to a 8
anyone can talk at this point
but I especially want to hear from the outliers
after anyone who wants to has had a chance to talk
each team member again picks a number from the cards in their hands
and then all at once the cards are revealed
this time let's say we get three fives in an eighth
at this point I'd ask Chris with his 8
to give us an impassioned plea for why 8 is the right estimate
I was with a team a little while ago
that had all weights except for 1 13
I asked the guy with a 13 why
boom boom boom he gave three good reasons why he thought it was a 13
and on the next round everyone switched to agree with him
so notice this isn't a vote
we don't say that the majority rules in pick a 5
we keep going until we get to a consensus
the consensus may be a little false
but that's okay
suppose we go another two or three rounds with Chris holding up an 8
while the rest of us have 5s
at that point I'd probably ask Chris if he thinks we've heard his arguments
but that we just disagree
if he does think we've heard him he will eventually fold and hold up a 5
I'm ok with Chris folding
after all the difference between 8 and 5 isn't that great
and we're pretty far up the effort accuracy curve
we saw a few minutes ago
now if Chris had been holding up a 100 instead of an 8
I wouldn't want him to fold
if we're that far apart we're probably facing one of two problems
one product uncertainty
which is the product owner saying something like
good question
I better run that by some users it could go either way
or to
technical uncertainty
which is when the team thinks that doing the user story will be easy
if they use one particular technical approach but hard if they take another approach
so whether its product uncertainty or technical uncertainty
if the estimates are hopelessly far apart put the story aside
do the research and then estimate the user story next week or whenever you get together again
or consider using a range if reducing the uncertainty will take more effort than you want to
or can invest
if team members ask the product owner what type of bear koala bear or grizzly bear
and the product owner can't say
your best option is to write down five to a hundred
one challenge with relative estimating is
how to get started
my recommendation is for team members to look at the product backlog
and find something they want to call a 2
don't play planning poker quite yet just find it 2
something small but not the smallest
I don't want you to waste time doing a bubble sort on your product backlog
looking for the smallest item
instead someone on the team to one user story and says that one's it 2
team members can argue if they disagree
but they keep at it until the team finds one user story
that everyone can agree is a 2
then look for a 5
remember we're only really good across one order of magnitude
so finding a 2 and a 5 establishes us a good baseline across most of that order of magnitude
I don't really care if you find a 2 and a 5
maybe you find a 1 and a 5 or a 2 and 8
any of those is fine
the idea is just to get a pair of numbers that everyone agrees on
and then start playing planning poker
I want to mention briefly that if you're looking for planning poker cards
we do sell the cards at our cost on our website at store mountaingoatsoftware.com
also we have a free website you can use for playing planning poker with a distributed team
in the next video we will look at some of the reasons why planning poker works