in this module we're going to move up a level to release planning
and take a look at how we estimate the product backlog
remember that the product backlog is a repository of everything
the product owner would like to have created over the life of the project
most teams tend to write their product backlog in the form of user stories
short simple statements told from the perspective of a user as I've shown here
throughout this module we're going to look at two different units
that agile teams commonly use for estimating their product backlogs
story points  and ideal days
we'll discuss the merits of each and by the end of this next set of videos
you'll have decided which unit you prefer
if you already have a preference by the end of this module
you'll be prepared with additional arguments in favor of that preference
think of it as a debate between the metric system and the English system
that is should we measure distance in kilometers or miles
that's what we'll be deciding in this module
before we really jump into things
I want to ask you to do a short exercise
I'd like you to estimate two things for me
first
tell me how long it will take to read the final Harry Potter book
you can see it here in this box to set
next estimate how long it will take you to drive from where you are to someplace pretty far away
since I don't know where you are I can't pick that place
pick a destination yourself that's pretty far
probably not somewhere you can drive in a day
and not somewhere you drive frequently
I'm here in Denver Colorado right now
I might pick some place like Detroit
as you do this don't cheat and look up on the internet how many pages the Harry Potter book is
or how many miles or kilometers away your destination is
I'm not really interested in their real numbers
and besides it's not like I'm going to ask you what your estimates are
but I do want you to pause this presentation and estimate these two things
the goal is to learn something about how we estimate real-world work
our goal isn't to come up with perfect estimates right now
okay pause this video now and restart it once you've estimated drive and reading of the seventh Harry Potter book
let me guess at some of the ways you might have estimated these two activities
one thing you might have done is compared to the thing being estimated to some other thing
you might for example have looked at the last Harry Potter book
and thought it was similar to the previous book the thick green one here
but a little longer
so you tried to recall how long it took you to read the sixth book
and then increase that amount by a little to come up with your estimate
this is called estimation by analogy and it's a great way to estimate
estimating by analogy is an important technique
and when we're going to rely on here as we build up a good estimation approach
another technique you may have used in estimating either the driving or the reading
is to first think about the size of the work estimate your pace through the work
and then divide to come up with an estimate of the duration
let's see how this might have worked with Harry Potter
perhaps you estimated the size of the book at six hundred pages
you then estimated that you read say one page every minute and a half
that means 40 pages per hour
dividing 600 pages by 40 pages per hour gives us an estimate of 15 hours
this is a great way to estimate
you may have done it for the driving example
by thinking about how many miles or kilometers away your destination was
and then dividing that by an estimated speed per hour
having seen how we estimate real-world activities like driving or reading
in the next video
we will turn what we just learned into one of the most valuable principles of agile estimating