Scrum teams are self-organizing and cross-functional
these characteristics are often misunderstood
so let's talk about what they mean in the context of Scrum
a Scrum team is self-organizing
meaning that the team chooses how best to accomplish their work
rather than being directed by others outside the team
within the Scrum framework, the team has total autonomy to choose how things get done
how do you estimate in Scrum?
ask the team!
what technical practices should be used?
what tools should we use to track our work?
ask the team!
how is work distributed during the sprint?
the traditional approach to organizing teams
is to do so by skillset or job title
for example, all of the researchers might be on one team,
sales on another,
engineeing another,
and marketing on yet another team
this structure results in a relay race approach
to delivering new products and services
which impedes speed,
flexibility, and quality
instead, Scrum teams are cross-functional
meaning that the members of the team
have all competencies needed to accomplish the work
without depending on others not part of the team