the daily meeting during the sprint is a
critical component of making teams
successful
and from the beginning we've always had the three questions that
needed to be asked
had to do what an each person do ,what are they going to do
and are there any problems or impediments getting in their way
now it turns out when people start scrum
people think it's all about them but it's not
about them. it's about the team
the goal is for the team to perform as well as
possible
so if you have a really dynamic team, person will say I did this
yesterday; I had these problems.
the team might in a very quick time have some
ideas about how to correct those problems
I'm going to do this today. the
team members may say well how are you going to do that
at when that's
described they may say hey you know another member of the team; I can help
you
we could get this done in an hour together
the way you're going to do it
alone it may take a day or two so
so let's work together to make it go faster
and so it's all about the team talking each person talking about what they've
done, what they're going to do,
but the
team figuring out together how that's going to work really well and really
fast
so that dynamic of teams helping one another out during that daily
meeting is really important
the meeting is short it's only 15 minutes
so and
many of the teams I've worked with they've had a 60 second rule
you know we
can talk about one issue for no more than 60 seconds
if we don't solve it by
then we'll kick it into a later meeting right after the scrum meeting to make
sure we finish it in 15 minutes
so these dynamics of the way that meeting works
are extremely critical
and there are many teams that need a lot of coaching
to get that right
you