in this video we'll learn all about the
sprint planning meeting we will cover
the inputs to the meeting the goals who
attends the time box the general
approach to running the meeting and the
outputs as its name implies the sprint
planning meeting is used to plan the
work of the sprint the meeting doesn't
happen before the sprint starts but is
the first event within the sprint this
is true of all scrum events everything
happens within a sprint and there is no
pause between sprints the sprint
planning meeting has two primary goals
first determine what can be delivered in
the sprint and second to plan how to
achieve that delivery the entire scrum
team attends the sprint planning meeting
the product owners role tends to be more
active during discussions of what can be
delivered and less active while the
development team plans how to achieve
the delivery participating as questions
arise the sprint planning meeting is
time boxed to eight hours for a
one-month sprint for shorter sprints the
time box is shorter a standard guideline
is two hours of planning for every one
week of sprint remember a time box is a
maximum amount of time not a minimum or
suggested amount of time many
experienced scrum teams regularly spend
far less than the time box in sprint
planning all scrum events are time boxed
with a limited amount of time the team
feels a sense of urgency to accomplish
the goals of the time boxed event nearly
all people work most effectively when
there are realistic but honored
deadlines in place since the team knows
there is limited time they tend to focus
on accomplishing the most important
things during that time skilled scrum
masters use the time box as a reason to
move the conversation along when it is
not serving the
meetings purpose in this way time boxes
are a constraint that help focus on the
value we can add by collaborating
Parkinson's law states that work expands
to fill the time allotted in everyday
terms this means that a meeting that is
scheduled for one hour will tend to take
the full hour regardless of what gets
accomplished rather than allotting the
exact amount of time a scrum event will
take scrum specifies the maximum time
the time box a skilled scrum master will
help the team focus only on
accomplishing the goals of the meeting
experienced scrum teams should find that
many scrum events are accomplished well
before the time box expires the sprint
planning meeting is typically divided
into two parts historically these were
referred to as Part A and Part B though
that language is not part of the current
official scrum guide instead the scrum
guide refers to two topics of discussion
related to the two goals what can be
delivered and how will we deliver it the
four inputs to the meeting are the
latest product increment if the Sprint
is for ongoing development the current
product backlog the projected capacity
of the development team during this
sprint and past performance of the
development team the first two inputs
the increment and product backlog help
us inspect and adapt on the product
itself what is the most important thing
to deliver which we can use to craft the
Sprint goal the second two inputs are
related to understanding how much can we
take on
past performance is helpful guidance to
the team to understand what on average
they can achieve during a given sprint
an analogy from the sports world is that
historic performance would be like the
average number of points scored per game
for a team over the course of an entire
season it is a good long-term guideline
capacity in the sports analogy would be
to look at tonight's game assessing who
is on the active roster whether the team
might be fatigued from the recent
schedule and the strengths and
weaknesses of tonight's opponent a scrum
team might consider various individuals
plan to time off or other commitments
inside and out of work the specific
product backlog items under
consideration and what skills are
required to deliver them any holidays
that might fall within the Sprint etc
with these inputs in place the scrum
team enters into the first topic of
discussion what can be achieved in the
sprint this is accomplished by the scrum
team collaborating to understand all of
the inputs and finally by the
development team polling product backlog
items into the Sprint only the
development team can make this
assessment of what to pull into the
sprint and any attempt by others outside
of the development team will lead to
some sort of dysfunction and typically
to a reduction in quality experience
scrum teams tend to spend very little
time on the first topic since they
actively refine the product backlog on
an ongoing basis once the development
team has made their forecasts for what
can be achieved in the Sprint the entire
scrum team collaborates to choose a
sprint goal the Sprint goal helps
clarify the overarching purpose of the
Sprint understanding the purpose and
impact of the work is a critical factor
in creating high-performing teams with
the selected product backlog items and a
sprint goal in place the scrum team
moves into the second topic of
discussion how will the chosen work get
done the selected
product backlog items are now contained
in the sprint backlog which is the
development teams plan for the sprint
they collaborate to design the system
and decompose the work required to
deliver the selected product backlog
items these details are added to the
sprint backlog effective development
teams tend to decompose all work into
small units that can be completed in no
more than a day or two the ensure that
all work required to meet the team's
definition of done is captured in the
sprint backlog as the development team
creates the sprint backlog they may
discover that the work was larger than
forecasted in which case they discuss
with the product owner what might be
removed while still meeting the Sprint
goal or if the Sprint goal should be
revised the product owner also answers
any new questions that arise about the
details of the product backlog items
that have been selected when the meeting
is complete
the development team should be able to
explain how they plan to act as a
self-organizing unit to deliver a
working product increment that meets the
Sprint goal and contains all of the
capabilities represented by the selected
product backlog items the outputs of the
sprint planning meeting then are a
finalized sprint goal and the
development team sprint backlog with
those in place the development team is
ready to begin working on the items in
the sprint backlog