as we learned in a previous section
scrum is an empirical approach to
managing work that means that each of
the scrum events is meant to increase
transparency so that the team can
reliably inspect their progress and
adapt their plans to better reach a
desired outcome in this section we'll
get an overview of how all of the scrum
events work together as a system in
future sections we'll take a closer look
at each event covering the why who and
how in more detail the Sprint is the
heartbeat of scrum it can be viewed as a
container for all of scrums inspect and
adapt loops the scrum team delivers a
new iteration of the working product
every sprint each sprint lasts at most
one calendar month and shorter sprints
are extremely common at the beginning of
the sprint the scrum team comes together
in the sprint planning meeting to assess
which items from the top of the product
backlog they can pull into the sprint
the team crafts a sprint goal a
high-level objective that will be
accomplished by delivering the selected
product backlog items the Sprint goal
helps ensure a shared understanding of
the purpose of the work in the coming
Sprint they then create the sprint
backlog which is the development teams
plan for how they will deliver the new
product increment once sprint planning
is complete the development team begins
their development work which continues
until the end of the sprint
once a day they will meet together at
the daily scrum meeting to inspect the
sprint plan and make any adaptations
necessary when the Sprint is complete
they will deliver a releasable product
increment they inspect that increment
along with other stakeholders at the
sprint review meeting and adapt their
future plans for the product by updating
the product backlog finally the scrum
team will hold a sprint retrospective to
inspect the system of work itself and
make adaptations to be more effective in
future sprints
scrum teams should have consistent
sprint lengths Sprint's provide a rhythm
to the work of the team and the business
instead of adjusting the length of each
sprint to match the upcoming work in the
product backlog effective scrum teams
learned to refine product backlog items
such that several could fit in any given
sprint the maximum sprint length is one
calendar month and the majority of scrum
teams today used two week sprints
providing twice as many opportunities to
inspect and adapt over time no new work
can be pushed into the sprint in scrum
the only way for work to be part of a
sprint is for the development team to
pull it in as discussed earlier this is
one of the primary purposes of the
sprint planning meeting
if a development team finds that they
have additional capacity while the
Sprint is in progress they may choose to
pull additional work into the sprint at
all times
meeting the Sprint goal is the guiding
principle if as is more common the work
turns out to be different than the
development team expected they
collaborate with the product owner to
negotiate the scope of Sprint backlog
within the Sprint the product owner may
choose to cancel a sprint this might
happen if for example the Sprint goal
becomes obsolete market conditions
change or the company makes a major
strategy change sprint cancellations are
rare since Sprint's are intentionally
short