one of the most common problems facing
early-stage scrum teams is when the
programmers finish on or near the last
day of the Sprint and then hand their
work over to the testers the testers are
left to wonder how they can possibly
complete their work in such a short time
similarly testers on such teams struggle
with what they're supposed to do earlier
in the sprint when there's nothing yet
to test nearly every team goes through a
phase where they face these problems so
if you're facing them now take heart
that others have overcome them before
you I want to make three suggestions as
to how you can resolve this problem
first get the programmers out of the
habit of finishing an entire product
backlog item before handing it over to
the testers handoffs between programmers
and testers should be much smaller
second make the problem more visible by
putting up a new chart in your team room
or project home page if the team is
distributed third help the team learn
new ways of collaborating through a
technique called swarming I'll talk
about each of these approaches but let's
start with number one getting the
programmers out of the habit of
finishing an entire product backlog item
before handing it over to the testers a
good scrum team should be doing a little
bit of everything every day I should be
able to walk into your team room any day
and see some analysis some design some
coding and some testing all happening to
make this a reality it's important for
team members to reduce the size of
handoffs let's consider the case of a
programmer and tester but this example
could just as easily include technical
designers user interface designers
database engineers or any number of
others if our example programmer and
tester are new to scrum it's likely that
the programmer will grab a product
backlog item finish the whole thing a
week or more later and then hand it over
to the tester for testing on the last
few days of the Sprint what that
programmer should do instead is develop
just one small part of the product
backlog item and then hand just that one
part to the tester
consider the case of a simple user story
about logging in as a user I can log in
so that I have access to my data this
user story can have detail added to it
in the form of conditions of
satisfaction which are really high level
acceptance tests for a user story the
conditions of satisfaction for our login
story may include these the right
credentials grant access can login
through Facebook wrong credentials
display an error message can request a
password reminder our programmer and
tester get together and decide where to
start
granting access when the right
credentials are entered seems like a
good place to start to me so the
programmer goes off and develops only
that while the programmer is coding the
tester is creating test plans test data
and automated tests the tester won't be
able to run these tests until the
programmer says the code is ready and in
some cases the tester may have a hard
time fully automating but in most cases
for most applications I've encountered
the tester can do a tremendous amount in
advance of receiving final code from a
programmer when both the programmer and
tester are done they check their work
into the official build system and the
tests are run they then talk about what
to work on next let's say they choose
Facebook integration again while the
programmer develops the functionality
the tester creates test plans data and
automation scripts there are still
handoffs here there are still moments
when the programmer yells out it's done
you can run the tests but the handoffs
have been made very small and between
each handoff both team members are
working on their parts of the feature
sometimes just describing this way of
working is enough for a team to adopt it
other teams need a bit more of a nudge
so let's look at the second thing I said
I like to do to address this problem put
up a new chart the chart graphs the
number of finished product backlog items
per day of the sprint often the graph
will look like this with the team
clearly expecting to finish all of
they're planned product backlog items in
the last two days of the sprint it's not
likely usually I put a graph like this
up without any fanfare I don't even
mention it I just hang it on the wall
near the team's task board or sprint
burn down chart the axes are clearly
labeled so it's not hard for the team to
figure out what the chart is showing if
the team doesn't get the hint from me
quietly posting and updating this I will
talk to them about it
I'll ask things like how do you expect
to finish eighth product backlog items
in two days when none have been finished
so far or are there ways we can find to
work together better so that we can
start finishing some user stories
earlier in the sprint one thing you can
do to help the team find those better
ways to work together is the third
suggestion of this video
swarm swarming refers to having the
entire team working on a single product
backlog item at once for most teams this
is never something I'd suggest
permanently but it can be great as a
drill I like to swim a common swimming
drill is called closed fist swimming you
swim with your hands clenched in fists
this is clearly inefficient and you'd
never want to race this way but it helps
a swimmer learn to feel the water on the
rest of their arm and the swimmer
develops a better stroke because of it
swarming is similar not something to do
permanently but great to try during the
occasional sprint when five to nine
people work on a single product backlog
item they will be forced to find new
ways to collaborate they'll find ways to
split the work into smaller parts
discover new ways to pair and so on
applying these three suggestions
programmers and testers working together
on subsets of a product backlog item
putting up a chart to make the issue
visible and swarming should help solve
the problem of programmers finishing
work too late for the testers to fully
test it